<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
"EN-US">Toyota adds some zip to Camry
<br /></span></strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US"
xml:lang="EN-US"><br />
Many 1987 cars are merely warmed-over 1986 models.
<br />
Not so with the 1987 Toyota Camry. The car shows Toyota, once
criticized for being too conservative, is working hard to offer
advanced, innovative models despite its success.
<br />
I never understood why the old Toyota Camry, introduced in 1982,
was so popular. It wasn&#39;t very quick, didn&#39;t handle
especially well and had bland styling.
<br />
The old, compact-size Toyota Camry illustrated just how
conservative Toyota was. I tested a Camry four years ago and was
surprised at how much it reminded me of the then-new mid-size cars
from General Motors.
<br />
The old Toyota Camry was successful because it carried Toyota&#39;s
revered nameplate in a huge market segment filled with many who
don&#39;t expect much from cars. The car also had a reputation for
being trouble-free.
<br />
I tested a 1987 Toyota Camry, which shouldn&#39;t be any less
reliable, and found it a vast improvement in all areas.
<br />
For one thing, the car finally has lively acceleration. Gone is the
95-horsepower four-cylinder with its conventional design. New is a
sweetheart of a twin-camshaft engine with a performance 16-valve
design.
<br />
The four-cylinder generates 115 horsepower and more torque and zips
the car from 0-60 m.p.h. in 11.5 seconds.
<br />
Two transmissions are available: a five-speed manual and
Toyota&#39;s four-speed Electronically Controlled Transmission
(ECT) that allows a driver to change transmission shift points to
match driving conditions. In the ECT&#39;s &quot;power&quot; mode,
the transmission shifts at higher revolutions per minute for more
responsive performance.
<br />
Toyota is wary some might not trust such an advanced, racing
oriented engine. The automaker stresses that it&#39;s a leader in
&quot;reliable four-valve-per-cylinder engine technology&quot; and
that the engine is a &quot;low-maintenance&quot; unit.
<br />
Not to worry. It should be just that, although it gets overly noisy
when revved hard.
<br />
Fuel economy is a government-estimated 27 m.p.g. city, 34 highway
with the manual and 25 and 31 with the automatic. Toyota Camry
owners shouldn&#39;t be stopping much for gasoline, thanks to the
good economy and new, larger 15.9-gallon tank.
<br />
The 1987 Toyota Camry looks like Toyota&#39;s top-line Cressida.
The four-door body isn&#39;t innovative, but it is slick and has a
respectable .34 drag coefficient for low wind noise.
<br />
New to the 1987 Toyota Camry lineup is a four-door station wagon.
Toyota Camry sedan prices range from $10,798 for the base model
with the manual to $13,398 for the top line LE model with the ECT.
Wagon prices range from $11,488 to $14,168.
<br />
The old 102.4-inch wheelbase is retained, but the new Toyota Camry
sedan is nearly seven inches longer. It&#39;s also slightly wider.
<br />
Interior room is good, accommodating four adults, and cargo
capacity is up 10 percent to 15.4 cubic feet. Instrumentation is in
the European tradition, with analog gauges that are easily read.
Controls are nicely placed for easy use.
<br />
The front bucket seats are comfortable and offer decent support.
<br />
The interior is filled with too much plastic, but plush velour
upholstery is standard on the top-line LE sedan and wagon.
<br />
A new convenience feature on the LE sedan and all wagons are 60/40
split-folding rear seats. With the rear seats folded down, the
Toyota Camry wagon has 65.1 cubic feet of cargo space.
<br />
The steering is a little light, but is quick and accurate. The ride
is quite good, thanks partly to gas-pressurized shock absorbers.
Brakes are confidence-inspiring.
<br />
Handling is above-average, helped by new, 14-inch rims - up from
the too-thin 13-inches on previous Camrys. The car&#39;s standard
all-season tires offer good grip.
<br />
Automatic shoulder belts, similar to those used on the Cressida
since 1981, are standard, as are 5-m.p.h. bumpers. However, lap
belts must be manually bucked.
<br />
Also standard is a tilt steering wheel with a &quot;memory&quot;
that enables a driver to return the wheel to a pre-selected
position - always a neat feature if there&#39;s more than one
driver in the family.
<br />
At one time, top-line radios only were offered in top-line cars.
But the Toyota Camry has an audio system that provides
pre-programmed equalization curves in five music formats - classic,
pop, rock, jazz or vocal.
<br />
All 1987 Toyotas are covered by more-comprehensive warranties that
have been extended to three years/36,000 miles from two
years/24,000 miles.
<br />
The new Toyota Camry with its 16-valve engine makes most
competitors look technically backward. It&#39;s terribly practical,
but also a lot of fun to drive.
<br />
<br /></span>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style=""><span style=""
    lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Dan Jedlicka</span></span></span>
    <br />
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style=""><span style=""
    lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Chicago
    Sun-Times</span></span></span>
    <br />
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;"><span style=""><span style=""
    lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">December 20,
    1986</span></span></span>
    <br />
</div><strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
"EN-US"><br /></span></strong>]]></text>
</root>