<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Root for 66 // M.P.G., that is, in Toyota&#39;s new
    Prius hybrid electric vehicle</span></strong>
</p>It&#39;s always nice to get a jump on the future.
<br />
For instance, imagine buying an affordable, ultra-low-emission car
within two years that delivers 66 m.p.g. in heavy traffic - and
runs 850 miles on a 13.2-gallon tank of gasoline during a mix of
city and highway driving.
<br />
Those figures aren&#39;t misprints. Such an auto has been offered
since last December in Japan, where 10,000 have been sold.
<br />
The car is Toyota&#39;s Prius, which is the world&#39;s first
mass-produced gasoline/electric hybrid vehicle.
<br />
This is no cramped, noisy, ugly auto. The quiet Toyota Prius looks
slick and has the safety, comfort, driveability and performance of
a regular compact sedan, I found while recently testing a Japanese
right-hand-drive version in the Loop and in fast traffic on the
Stevenson Expy.
<br />
Four 6-footers - or five in a pinch - easily fit in the Toyota
Prius because it has a fairly long 100.4-inch wheelbase and
excellent space utilization. Steering and handling are sharp, and
the ride is comfortable.
<br />
The Toyota Prius will debut in the United States in late 2000. By
then, it likely will offer better performance because Toyota said
it will use the next two years to &quot;further optimize the car
for local driving conditions outside Japan.&quot;
<br />
For instance, the Toyota Prius now does 0 to 60 m.p.h. in 14
seconds, but Toyota spokesman John McCandless said the company
wants to cut that time to 11 seconds for the U.S. model.
<br />
The Toyota Prius uses a high-efficiency 1.5-liter gasoline engine
and electric motor. It operates on electricity at low speeds and
switches automatically to the overhead-camshaft gasoline engine at
higher speeds, depending on load and driving conditions.
<br />
Power is supplied by both the electric and gasoline motors in
high-load situations. The 2,750-pound car has nearly 100 horsepower
when both power units are activated and can hit 100 m.p.h. Toyota
said the Toyota Prius should be a low-maintenance vehicle and that
its nickel-metal hydride batteries will last for 150,000 miles.
<br />
&quot;The Toyota Prius is far and away the best alternative yet to
a conventional car,&quot; said auto analyst Jim Wangers of
Automotive Marketing Consultants in Vista, Calif. &quot;Its appeal
should be especially strong in congested areas.&quot;
<br />
David Cole, director of the Office for the Study of Automotive
Transportation at the University of Michigan, said the university
sees &quot;substantial growth in the market for hybrid vehicles by
2007.&quot;
<br />
&quot;Some 5 percent of passenger cars are expected to be hybrids
in auto model year 2007. That&#39;s about 400,000 hybrids - a
pretty significant number.&quot;
<br />
As for the Toyota Prius, he characterized it as a &quot;terrific
first start for a hybrid vehicle. It gives lots of credibility to
the potential for such vehicles.&quot;
<br />
Still, auto analyst Ray Windecker of Michigan&#39;s American
AutoDatum isn&#39;t sure if the Toyota Prius will be a hit in this
country.
<br />
&quot;Unlike the Japanese, most Americans haven&#39;t responded
well to high-tech cars such as the Toyota Prius because they
don&#39;t see them as necessary,&quot; Windecker said.
&quot;Americans really would start paying attention to the Toyota
Prius if there&#39;s another gasoline supply crunch.&quot;
<br />
The only rival to the Toyota Prius is General Motors&#39; electric
car. While sleek and lively, the GM car isn&#39;t very practical
because it has only a 120-mile range - at best. It&#39;s offered
only in a few warm-weather states because it isn&#39;t suited to
cold-weather operation. Only several hundred of the GM electric
autos have found takers.
<br />
The GM vehicle generally has flopped because of its limited range
and because it must be plugged into an electrical outlet to
recharge its batteries.
<br />
The Toyota Prius never needs to be plugged in. Its hybrid system
design allows it to recharge its batteries by routing power from
the gasoline engine to an electric generator.
<br />
With the Toyota Prius, one just fills its tank at any gasoline
station. It runs as efficiently as a regular car in cold weather,
and also will be sold in Canada.
<br />
&quot;The GM electric car basically has been a good public
relations stunt,&quot; Wangers said. &quot;The Toyota Prius
represents a huge breakthrough mostly because it never needs to be
plugged in. It should have worldwide appeal, especially in
congested metropolitan areas.&quot;
<br />
GM&#39;s electric car can only be leased, but Americans will be
able to either lease or buy the Toyota Prius.
<br />
Price? The Toyota Prius costs $16,000 in Japan, but is expected to
cost a few thousand dollars more here.
<br />
&quot;We anticipate that many Americans will lease the Toyota Prius
so they can try it out without making a long-term commitment,&quot;
said Mark Amstock, alternative fuel vehicle planning manager for
Toyota&#39;s U.S. operation.
<br />
Toyota said &quot;no rocket science&quot; is involved in the Toyota
Prius design. But it&#39;s a clever design, nevertheless. It was
almost impossible to tell when the Toyota Prius was switching from
electric to gasoline power - or when both power units begin working
together under full-throttle acceleration.
<br />
When stopped, the gasoline engine isn&#39;t running and the
electric motor automatically shuts off to conserve battery power.
Press the accelerator and the car instantly accelerates smartly.
<br />
This clearly is a radical new car.
<br />
<p class="MsoNormal" style=
"margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; line-height: normal; text-align: right;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US"><span style=""><span style="">Dan
    Jedlicka</span></span></span><span style="font-size: 12pt;"
    lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"><br />
    <span style=""><span style="">Chicago
    Sun-Times</span></span></span> <span style="font-size: 12pt;"
    lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"><br />
    <span style=""><span style="">September 14,
    1998</span></span></span>
</p>
<br />]]></text>
</root>