<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <strong><span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;"
    xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Toyota Sequoia ranks as big
    SUV.</span></strong>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Once so wary of a
    potential buy-American backlash that it postponed the debut of
    a full-size pickup truck, Toyota now seems determined to butt
    heads with Ford and General Motors on the front line of nearly
    every truck segment.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Among its more
    recent <span style="font-weight: bold;">new truck entries is
    the Sequoia sport utility vehicle</span>. Nearly a foot longer
    and a couple of inches wider than its SUV flagship Land
    Cruiser, Toyota Sequoia is roughly the size of Ford&#39;s
    Expedition. Although larger than Land Cruiser, it is priced
    about $10,000 less.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Bolted together in
    Indiana, Sequoia gives Toyota entry into the mainstream
    full-size SUV market. It is aimed at the customer currently
    buying Chevy Tahoes, GMC Yukons and Expeditions. Sharing its
    platform with the Tundra pickup, Toyota Sequoia enjoys almost
    11 inches of ground clearance - a segment best. It is
    configured with either two-wheel or four-wheel drive, and is
    offered in two trim levels: the SR5 and higher-end Limited. My
    test Sequoia was a Limited 4x4.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">While they share a
    platform, front-end components and their V-8, Toyota Tundra and
    Toyota Sequoia are not the same vehicle with different bodies.
    Unlike Tundra, Sequoia&#39;s frame is fully boxed, the front
    independent suspension has been tweaked and a five-link coiled
    spring rear suspension replaces Tundra&#39;s leaf spring
    architecture. The end result is a quieter, less harsh
    ride.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Moreover, the V-8
    has been modified, requalifying it as an
    ultra-low-emission-vehicle from the low-emission-vehicle rating
    of Tundra. Although the V-8 gives up five horsepower in Toyota
    Sequoia, its numbers are still healthy at 240 horsepower and
    315 foot-pounds of torque. It is capable of towing 6,200 pounds
    when fitted with 4WD. It gains 300 pounds of towing capacity
    with just rear-wheel drive. A four-speed automatic transmission
    passes engine output to the wheels. Shifting from RWD to
    4WD-high is accomplished with a push of a button on the
    dashboard.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Tipping the scale
    at 5,300 pounds, the 4x4 Sequoia still manages to reach 60
    miles per hour from a stop in just over 10 seconds. As might be
    expected, fuel economy isn&#39;t a selling point. The
    Environmental Protection Agency rates the 4x4 Sequoia&#39;s
    miles per gallon at 14 in the city and 17 on the
    highway.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Toyota Sequoia is
    a truck and a big truck at that. Its ride, however, is calm
    over smooth surfaces. Rougher roads or no roads make things a
    bit livelier. Disc brakes are fitted to all four wheels. An
    anti-lock system is standard. Also standard are Vehicle Skid
    Control (VSC), and Traction Control (TRAC) or Active Traction
    Control (A-TRAC). VSC minimizes loss of control when cornering,
    while TRAC (2WD) and A-TRAC (4WD) minimizes loss of traction on
    slippery surfaces.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Sequoia&#39;s
    cabin is expansive. With seating for up to eight, it is as
    adept at transporting people as it is at hauling stuff. All
    seating positions have three-point seat belts. The 50/50 split
    rear seat not only folds and tumbles, it slides forward or back
    to accommodate longer legs or extra cargo. All controls and
    switches are neatly arranged.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Everything is easy
    to find and uncommonly simple to operate. There are 10 cup
    holders, six storage pockets and four 12-volt power outlets.
    The Limited comes with a 10-speaker JBL audio system, dual
    front/rear air conditioning system and leather interior.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Sequoia&#39;s
    height makes getting in and out a bit of a challenge, but the
    standard running boards solve the problem. Access to the rear
    cargo area is achieved by lifting the rear hatch or lowering
    the power rear window. Incidentally, the rear window will lower
    completely into the rear hatch.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Big, powerful and
    Toyota dependable, the Sequoia won&#39;t be a wallflower in the
    full-size SUV segment. And, with Sequoia being the biggest of
    trees, you have to wonder if it will also be the biggest of
    Toyota SUVs.</span>
</p>
<p>
    <span style="" xml:lang="EN-US" lang="EN-US">Base price of the
    Toyota Sequoia Limited 4x4 is $42,275. Standard features not
    already described include alloy wheels, dual front air bags,
    dual heated power retractable outboard mirrors, fog lamps,
    front captain&#39;s chairs, power windows and door locks, tilt
    steering wheel, cruise control, auto on/off headlamps, center
    console and automatic climate control. Adding the $495 delivery
    charge brought the final total to $42,770.</span>
</p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    <span style=""><span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;">
    Heaps, Russ</span></span>
    <br />
    <span style=""><span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;">
    The Washington Times</span></span>
    <br />
    <span style=""><span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;">
    April 13, 2001</span></span>
</div>]]></text>
</root>