<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Toyota&#39;s Sienna van
    improving with age</span></strong>
</p>As Toyota&#39;s Sienna minivan enters its fourth year, it
proves some vehicles age a bit more gracefully than others. Sure,
its rear seats may not be as easy to remove as some of the
redesigned competition, and the interior may not be quite as roomy,
but overall, there is an unmistakable impression of quality,
durability and safety.
<br />
All 2001 models arrive with a driver&#39;s-side sliding door. Dual
power sliding doors is a new option. Cosmetic enhancements include
a new front fascia, redesigned grille, freshened bumper and new
taillamps. Massaging the engine has resulted in more horsepower and
torque this year. Another noteworthy new option is the
entertainment center, with its fold-down monitor, videocassette
player with game input, handheld remote and two wireless
headphones. Although Toyota Sienna is aging, it isn&#39;t getting
old.
<br />
Built alongside the Toyota Camry in Kentucky, the Toyota Sienna
shares its platform and powertrain with the wildly popular sedan.
In fact, in many ways Toyota Sienna is like a Camry with seating
for seven. Also like the Camry, Sienna&#39;s exterior styling
won&#39;t turn many heads, but its lines are clean and pleasing to
the eye. Toyota has tried to make it more aerodynamic in appearance
by bringing the front end to a subtle V shape.
<br />
Sienna&#39;s plain-wrapper looks, however, aren&#39;t really a
factor. Minivan owners seem much more concerned with issues of the
interior than exterior styling. And Sienna&#39;s cabin stands up
remarkably well to comparisons with even its freshest competitors.
<br />
Available in three trim levels (CE, LE and XLE), Toyota Sienna can
be tailored to a family&#39;s needs and pocketbook. The entry-level
CE sells for $21,514, while the top-of-the-heap XLE has a suggested
base price of $28,436. Among other features, that extra $7,000 adds
such amenities as cruise control, power locks with remote keyless
entry, dual power outboard mirrors, upgraded audio system with
eight speakers and CD player, and anti-theft security system.
<br />
Utility is increased by both the standard driver&#39;s-side slider
and especially by the dual power doors option ($1,675 bundled with
power moon roof). Opening or closing these doors with arms full of
grocery bags can be accomplished with just a push of a button on
the keyless remote fob. Sienna&#39;s low step-in makes for ease of
entry and exit. The seats are firm, if a bit narrow. Opting for the
XLE package replaces the second-row bench seat with removable
captain&#39;s bucket seats. The split, folding third-row seat is
then somewhat easier to reach. With all the seats in place, there
is still some cargo room behind the third-row seat. In addition to
the third-row seatback folding down, the seat itself will tumble
forward or can be removed entirely.
<br />
Toyota has tinkered with the location of the audio and ventilation
system controls for more user-friendly placement. There are cup
holders and storage cubby holes galore.
<br />
Although, Camry&#39;s version doesn&#39;t benefit from the same
boost in power as Sienna&#39;s V-6 received this year, Sienna&#39;s
power plant and four-speed automatic transmission are lifted
directly from Toyota Camry. Sienna&#39;s three-liter V-6 now has
210 horsepower and 220 foot-pounds of peak torque, as opposed to
194 horsepower and 209 foot-pounds of torque last year. The extra
boost is particularly welcome when toting a full compliment of
passengers.
<br />
Coaxing more performance from the engine hasn&#39;t bruised fuel
economy at all. In fact, the Environmental Protection Agency rates
Sienna&#39;s around-town miles per gallon a mile better this year
at 19, while the highway mpg rating remains unchanged at 24. The
engine is quiet, and the transmission shifts with smooth precision.
Getting the needle from zero to 60 mph takes about 10 ticks of the
clock. It is a minivan, but it holds its own when the light turns
green.
<br />
In addition to features already mentioned, Toyota Sienna XLE&#39;s
base price of $28,436 also includes anti-lock brakes, dual front
air bags, 15-inch alloy wheels, low tire-pressure warning light,
rear wiper and washer, power windows, rear air conditioner and roof
rack.
<br />
The test Toyota Sienna XLE had $5,885 worth of options, such as
side air bags ($250), interior upgrade package ($1,610) with
leather seating, power driver&#39;s seat and JBL audio upgrade, and
the Vehicle Entertainment System ($1,495). Adding the $495 delivery
charge brought the price as tested to $34,816.
<br />
<br />
<div style="text-align: right;">
    Heaps, Russ
    <br />
    The Washington Times
    <br />
    March 2, 2001
</div>]]></text>
</root>