<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Smart Move.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">With a 4500-pound tow
    rating just for boats, the Acura MDX does the thinking for
    you</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The MDX is the first Acura
    I have tested, simply because the company did not have anything
    in the past that would merit a tow test. However, this new
    sport-utility vehicle (SUV) piqued my interest well before the
    test, due to its unique split tow ratings. When towing
    fixed-sided trailers, such as box trailers, it is rated for
    3500 pounds. For trailered boats, however, the MDX is rated for
    4500 pounds (see Jim Hendricks&#39; &quot;On Plane,&quot; on
    page 10).</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Having now put the MDX
    through a rigorous tow test, I can say that it is one of the
    most impressive SUVs ever built. I am particularly impressed
    with the automatic transmission/engine combination that does
    all the towing work usually performed by the driver, and a
    suspension that delivers excellent towing and non-towing
    stability at all speeds.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Sized similarly to the Ford
    Explorer, the MDX has a versatile, seven-passenger interior,
    with second- and third-row seats. The seats split and fold flat
    into the floor to accommodate a variety of passenger and
    cargo-carrying configurations.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The vehicle&#39;s offroad
    capabilities are considered to be medium-duty, without the
    extra, overwhelmingly beefy components that detract from
    on-road performance. However, the MDX comes with a deeper oil
    pan and a heavy-duty air filter for offroading. Waterproofing
    was also added to allow the MDX to traverse 18-inch-deep bodies
    of water. And the throttle linkage was calibrated to provide
    more sensitive control over engine output at low speeds. It
    also has a tight turning radius, making it easy to maneuver on
    twisty mountain roads and in tight parking lots.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Diminutive Dynamo</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">In case you are not
    familiar with Acura, it&#39;s built by American Honda, which
    has created some of the finest small power plants in the world,
    including racing engines. The MDX uses a 3.5L V-6. But
    don&#39;t be influenced by its diminutive displacement.
    It&#39;s a dynamite performer.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The all-aluminum,
    double-overhead camshaft (DOHC), 24-valve engine has a Variable
    Timing and Lift Electronic Control (VTEC) system. This allows
    the engine to produce 240 hp and 245 ft.-lbs. of torque. It
    delivers 95 percent of its peak torque (pulling power) from
    2000 to 5500 rpm, which is excellent for towing.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The V-6 has low-restriction
    intake and exhaust systems, a 10:1 compression ratio (which
    requires premium fuel), and roller-type rocker arms. A
    lightweight, forged-steel crankshaft is used for maximum
    strength, rigidity and durability.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Most engines have fixed
    valve-train parameters -- the same timing for valve lift and
    overlap, regardless of whether the engine is struggling to
    climb out of a low-rpm range or screaming at redline. But
    Acura/Honda&#39;s VTEC approach has two distinct modes -- it
    changes intake-valve operation to optimize volumetric
    efficiency (breathing) and combustion of the fuel-air mixture.
    Depending on engine speed, the rocker arms are electronically
    shifted to either the high-speed or low-speed lobes of the
    camshaft to provide a different range of performance.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Benefits Of Vtec</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">During the towing
    acceleration tests, I quickly learned how well the VTEC system
    worked. The air/fuel intake did its job so adeptly that seeing
    the tachometer shoot up quickly was the only noticeable change.
    What made acceleration so impressive was that the towing times
    were very close to the speed when I was not towing -- only
    tenths of a second apart.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Unlike other small engines,
    the 3.5L V-6 wants to run at interstate speeds when towing,
    even up moderate hills, without prodding. I chose not to use
    fourth or fifth gears on the hills; both gears were too tall.
    But more surprises were in store.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Every time I decided to
    downshift on an uphill, the transmission beat me to it. After a
    few of these one-upmanships by the transmission, I decided it
    wasn&#39;t necessary to downshift, because the tranny was
    holding lower gears just as long as I would if I were
    shifting.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">On flat ground at 55 and 65
    mph, I tried using fourth-gear overdrive. The tach dropped to
    2100 rpm. But, as I kept a watchful eye, it soon was up to 2400
    rpm, then varied between 2400 and 2700 rpm, which is a normal
    difference between the transmission&#39;s lockup and unlock
    systems. Then, when the grades got steeper, I was reading 3300
    rpm, with no feeling that it had dropped to third gear. I
    confirmed this by dropping the gearshift lever to third with no
    change in rpm. This was the VTEC and transmission playing their
    inconspicuous roles.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Dynamite Drivetrain</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A five-speed,
    electronically controlled, automatic transmission is standard
    on all models. It&#39;s the new VTM-4 (Variable Torque
    Management 4WD) -- a fully automatic, four-wheel-drive system.
    And it works integrally with the engine.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">When I first read about
    this wide-ratio, five-speed automatic, I expected lackluster
    towing performance because of the drop in engine speed on
    upshifts and the big burst of engine speed on downshifts. Not
    so.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Instead, the engine VTEC
    system &quot;read&quot; what was happening and corrected engine
    rpm before the transmission had a chance to balk, producing
    extremely smooth transitions between gears. The MDX is
    basically a front-wheel-drive vehicle (FWD), but you would
    never know it while driving.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Unlike other on-demand 4WD
    and all-wheel-drive (AWD) systems, the VTM-4 doesn&#39;t wait
    for slippage to happen. Instead, torque is delivered to the
    rear wheels in proportion to forward acceleration to supplement
    FWD. This has two advantages. First, on dry pavement, it is
    less likely to torque-steer (the tendency of the steering wheel
    to pull to one side during acceleration) and to provide more
    front-tire adhesion when cornering. In wet or snowy conditions,
    automatic AWD gets the vehicle moving with less chance of
    wheel-spin.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A button on the dash
    activates an exclusive lock feature. It allows the driver to
    send maximum torque (53 percent) to the rear wheels in
    extremely low-speed, low-traction or &quot;stuck&quot;
    situations. It works very well on launch ramps. The driver only
    needs to move the lever to one or more of the two lower forward
    gears or reverse, then touch a button on the dash. With the
    lock mode engaged, VTM-4 automatically reduces the transfer of
    torque to the rear axle at about 6 mph and reverts to front
    drive by 18 mph. When cruising, with no wheel-slip present, the
    system reverts to FWD for improved fuel economy.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Chassis</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">There was no bouncing or
    movement in the back of this vehicle when towing 4400 pounds
    with a light (240-pound) tongue weight. With the window open, I
    could hear the trailer bounce and make noise, but none of that
    action was being transferred to the tow vehicle.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">To overcome the usual ride
    vs. handling compromises, especially with a rigid uni-body, the
    MDX uses front and rear subframes to isolate road noise and
    drivetrain vibration from the passenger compartment. This is a
    procedure many uni-body makers use.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">These subframes house the
    front and rear suspension systems and provide extra wheel
    travel to complement the suspension. Low roll centers (for
    center of gravity) are combined with stiff anti-roll bars to
    provide progressive, predictable cornering response and
    excellent stability at the limit of adhesion. The
    rack-and-pinion steering has a very positive feel.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The MDX also has a wide
    track to maximize stability and cornering traction. The wide
    stance is said to be 2 1/2 to 4 3/4 inches wider than its
    closest competitor.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Braking Performance</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">To provide short stopping
    distances, fade-resistance and a reassuring pedal feel, the
    four-wheel disc-brake system uses large-diameter rotors and
    extra-rigid, single-piston calipers. The ABS features
    electronic distribution of brake force at all four
    wheels.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">In our case, the MDX had an
    exceptional non-towing stop of 94 feet, without a flaw or
    pedal-throb. And thanks to the trailer&#39;s Trailer Buddy
    brakes, braking when towing from 55 mph was only 116 feet --
    very good for a 4400-pound load and mid-size SUV.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Incidentally, for towing,
    Acura requires a dealer-installed transmission cooler for the
    MDX. Factory hitches and trailer wiring are also
    available.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">In the final analysis, the
    MDX came as a pleasant surprise. It provides good visibility,
    exceptional seating comfort, crisp handling, surprising
    performance and handles its maximum tow rating for boats very
    well.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">If there is any negative,
    it is the price -- $38,970. This includes a $2600 touring
    package -- seat and mirror memory system, eight-way
    power-adjustable passenger seat, roof rack, upgraded sound
    system with CD - and a $2000 navigation system.</span>
</p>
<p style="text-align: right;" class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Kovacik, Bob
    <br />
    Trailer Boats
    <br />
    February 1, 2001</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>