<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Acura 3.2TL slightly
    upgraded.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Restyled for last year, the
    Acura 3.2TL enters 2000 with only a few enhancements such as a
    new five-speed automatic transmission with SportShift and a new
    air bag system. The engine has also been massaged for quicker
    off-the-line acceleration and improved fuel economy.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Although 2000 doesn&#39;t
    signal sweeping changes for this automobile Acura refers to as
    its ultimate performance sedan, it obviously isn&#39;t resting
    on its laurels either.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">While Acura enjoyed about
    an 8 percent year-over-year sales increase in 1999, the TL was
    up more than 80 percent. This is even more remarkable when the
    rather flat sales performance of some of TL&#39;s closest
    competitors is taken into consideration.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">With its $29,000 price tag
    and staggering list of standard equipment, the 3.2TL is an easy
    sedan to buy on several levels. In the near- or entry-luxury
    segment, the TL stands out as a real value.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A key factor in the ease of
    purchase is not having to make too many decisions. If you want
    to make your head swim, try buying a full-size pickup truck
    where nearly everything is an option. Buying a TL is the
    antithesis of that experience. Engine, there is only one: a
    zesty 3.2-liter V-6. Transmission? There is only one of those,
    too. It is a five-speed automatic/manual that Acura calls its
    Sequential SportShift.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">At 225 horsepower and 216
    foot-pounds of peak torque, the key engine statistics
    haven&#39;t changed from last year; but Acura claims the 0-60
    mph time has been trimmed by about half a second. This was
    achieved primarily through enhancements to the engine&#39;s
    breathing system. I found the new TL took just over seven
    seconds to reach 60 mph from a standing stop. A bit less
    thirsty than last year&#39;s version, the new TL has earned a
    miles-per-gallon rating of 19 city and 29 highway.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Perched upon 16-inch tires,
    the fully independent suspension does an impressive job of
    soaking up broken pavement. With the emphasis on ride quality,
    handling is a bit of a compromise, but cornering is predictable
    and without theatrics. Wonderfully agile, the TL zips around
    the city with ease. A traction system is standard, and it
    operates at speeds below 25 mph, controlling wheel spin through
    the anti-lock brakes. Disc brakes on all four wheels bring the
    TL to sure-footed stops.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Comfortably spacious, the
    cabin is characterized by clean, simple lines. A number of
    subtle colors and textures add some interest to this interior.
    A little leather, a little wood grain, it all meshes together
    into a functional and handsome cockpit. Everything is easy to
    see, and for the most part, operate.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">My test Acura had the one
    factory-installed option. It&#39;s the Global Positioning
    System navigation with its screen positioned above the audio
    system controls. It also serves as the control center for the
    ventilation system, and here is where things get a little
    complicated. Once set, however, the climate control is good to
    go and probably won&#39;t have to be messed with anyway.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The seats are comfortable,
    and there is sufficient legroom for rear seat passengers.
    Likewise, cargo space is in ample supply and the bumper-high
    lift-over is a real plus. A credit to the narrow A- and
    C-pillars, visibility is excellent in all directions. Front
    side-impact air bags join the dual front air bags in supplying
    passive restraint. While the TL competes in the entry-luxury
    segment, its interior bespeaks a more expensive sedan.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Base price of the Acura
    3.2TL is $28,855. When opting for the navigational system, it
    is included into the sticker price, adding $1,545 to the total.
    The base price with navigational system is $30,400.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Included in this price and
    not already mentioned: height-adjustable front shoulder belts,
    high-intensity-discharge headlamps, dual power remote outboard
    mirrors, rear-window defroster, leather seating,
    leather-wrapped tilt steering wheel, eight-way power
    driver&#39;s seat, four-way power passenger seat, heated front
    seats, five-speaker Bose AM/FM stereo/cassette/compact disc
    player, redundant steering-wheel-mounted audio controls,
    speed-sensing intermittent wipers, power moon roof, auto
    day/night rearview mirror, auto-off headlamps, outside
    temperature gauge, power windows/door locks, keyless remote
    entry, anti-theft security system with electronic engine
    immobilizer and 16-inch alloy wheels. Adding the $455 delivery
    charge brought the price as tested to $30,855.</span>
</p>
<p style="text-align: right;" class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Heaps, Russ
    <br />
    The Washington Times
    <br />
    April 28, 2000</span>
</p>
<div style="text-align: right;"></div>
<p style="text-align: right;" class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&nbsp;</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>