<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A Rose Is A Rose; TSX
    stands out in its field.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">How appropriate that at
    least one Acura dealer out there surprised a customer by
    presenting her with flowers upon delivery of her new 2004 TSX.
    Whether the bouquet was roses or not is immaterial- in this
    case the car is the rose, by whatever brand name the Japanese
    automaker decides to stick on its decklid.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">In the TSX, U.S. buyers
    finally get a car based on the non-U.S. Honda Accord, the
    smaller, narrower, sportier Euro-Accord that debuted in late
    2002.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">As an Acura, TSX gets all
    the refined appointments and sporting character we&#39;ve come
    to expect from Honda&#39;s luxury lineup, backed by Honda
    reliability and precision build quality, all wrapped up in a
    Euro- performance package. Standard luxury goodies covered by
    the $26,990 base sticker price include perforated leather seats
    and leather-wrapped steering wheel with remote audio and cruise
    controls, power sunroof, a 360-watt audio system with eight
    speakers, dual-zone climate control, power windows and door
    locks and keyless entry. Toss in the optional Acura navigation
    system with voice recognition as the only option for
    $2,000.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">TSX&#39;s only engine is
    the 2.4-liter, 16-valve, dohc i-VTEC aluminum alloy
    four-cylinder, rated at 200 hp at 6800 rpm and 166 lb-ft of
    torque at 4500 rpm. The lack of a V6 engine option was actually
    a draw for most buyers, who saw the four-cylinder as more than
    powerful enough while also offering better fuel economy than a
    six.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Transmission choices
    include a close-ratio six-speed manual or a five-speed
    automatic with an autostick. Four-wheel independent suspension,
    four-wheel antilock disc brakes, stability control with
    traction control, rack-and-pinion steering, and 17-inch alloy
    wheels fitted with V-rated all-season performance tires
    complete the package.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">We raised an eyebrow when
    Acura suggested competition for the front-drive TSX would come
    not just from front/all-wheel-drivers like Audi A4, Volvo S40,
    Volkswagen Jetta and Passat and Nissan Altima, but also from
    rear-drivers like BMW 325, Lexus IS 300 and Mercedes-Benz
    C-Class. Turns out Acura&#39;s assessment was spot-on with
    AutoWeek readers, who reported considering or previously owning
    many of those marques before choosing TSX. Buyers told us they
    considered almost all of those models, as well as
    Infiniti&#39;s G35, the Jaguar X-Type and Saab 9-3. Perhaps
    unexpected (or maybe just left unmentioned by Acura) was that
    buyers also passed on Acura CL and TL models, as well as the
    Accord coupe, en route to settling on TSX.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">For buyers seeking
    sportiness in an upscale package, TSX fills the niche,
    competing head-to-head with more expensive competitors for
    interior quiet and comfort-with just a trace of a nice raspy
    exhaust note. And while rugged levels of torque steer are often
    the norm in front-drive sports cars, we detected not a trace of
    sideways pull, even under severe acceleration from a standing-
    start. We found the engine and drivetrain very smooth across
    the powerband.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">TSX also received high
    marks in handling, offering quick steering response and smooth
    sailing through the slalom. On the skidpad (with stability
    control off), we found the handling very predictable and
    throttle-controllable, without any bump-induced upset.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The Accord coupe, at a
    nearly identical curb weight, is still a better choice for
    performance-oriented buyers, according to our test results.
    Compared with the Accord we tested (AW, March 3), the TSX was
    more than a second slower from 0 to 60 mph and almost a second
    slower in the quarter-mile. The TSX and the Accord coupe were
    comparable in roll-ing acceleration from 20 to 40 mph, and in
    braking.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Performance aside, owners
    told us the Acura&#39;s high level of standard equipment vs.
    the competition made their purchase decision easy. They lauded
    TSX&#39;s interior appointments (and its blue-hued ambient
    illumination, in particular), as well as its somewhat staid
    exterior styling. Said one owner, &quot;The TSX has been
    criticized by the media for bland styling, but it will look
    better in five or 10 years than many new cars with more
    gimmicky styling.&#39;&#39;</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Kind of like a rose.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">AutoWeek</span>
    <br />
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">August 4, 2003</span>
</div>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>]]></text>
</root>