<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Audi racing ahead in the
prestige brand market
<br /></span></strong>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The new car merry-go round is
    spinning fast at Audi. And the firm is pushing the pace as it
    cements its place among the world&#39;s prestige brands.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The last couple of years have
    seen new models come hard and fast. We&#39;ve seen the super
    impressive Audi A8, high performance S4, the dual-purpose
    Allroad, the latest Audi A6 and a second generation baby A3,
    the first generation of which sold 875,000 worldwide.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The Audi A3 is the starter car
    in the Audi family line-up and runs hard up against some of the
    toughest rivals in the business - starting with the BMW
    1-Series, but including everything from the Alfa Romeo 147 to
    Volvo&#39;s smart and impressive new S40.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The look is new, but the real
    innovation is in the mechanical package. The pricing is pretty
    sharp, too - starting at pounds 15,510 for the 1.6-litre entry
    level model.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">There is no escaping the
    mechanical links between the Audi A3 and the fifth generation
    Golf because both come from the Volkswagen Group family, but
    the prestige leader can claim the high ground as it hit the
    road first.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">Audi manages to do it with
    everything from a new suspension system to electromechanical
    power steering as well as a major first - a direct fuel
    injection system as fitted to my test car. That&#39;s on top of
    active head restraints and an electronic stabilitysystem for
    safety.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The FSI engine comes with 150PS
    of power and 147lb/ft of torque but Audi is rightly making big
    claims about the car&#39;s response, economy and efficiency
    rather than its out-andout performance.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">For the record it will sprint to
    62mph in just over nine seconds and top 130mph in the right
    conditions. Out on the open road it will average over 40mpg
    which is better than good for any sporty two-litre
    hatchback.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">It didn&#39;t take me long to
    warm to the Audi A3. It could have been the look or just the
    overall refinement. Audi obviously takes a lot of trouble over
    build quality although I think the car&#39;s superb fit and
    finish hides some of its personality.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The Audi A3 is a top car and
    very enjoyable but you have to dig quite deep to expose its
    inner strengths. They come from the responsive and refined
    engine and a suspension that copes easily with bumps and
    curves.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The Audi A3 makes a strong first
    impression, thanks to a cabin that must be the benchmark in its
    class and which reflects Audi&#39;s commitment to producing the
    best-quality cockpits in the business. It is everything from
    the red leather seats in the test car andred lit night lights
    to the panel shut gaps, quality finishes and the combination of
    materials used.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">Powered by the two-litre petrol
    engine, which uses a common rail system identical to that in
    diesel cars for extra fuel efficiency, the FSI gets along very
    nicely with a combination of light and easy cruising and
    foot-down fun.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">Audi has made the Audi A3 feel
    more agile than before with a more sophisticated suspension so
    that it doesn&#39;t lean quite so much through bends as one of
    Sir Richard Branson&#39;s Pendolino high-speed trains.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The result is it tracks round
    bends as if it was on a TGV line, by which I mean it
    doesn&#39;t alter its angle mid-corner if you play about with
    the accelerator when going briskly.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The engine is sweet and
    responsive which means you can glide along motorways.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">The six-speed manual gearbox,
    with its crisp and instant changes, is among the best I&#39;ve
    ever used. In fact, the whole Audi A3 experience is smart and
    impressive - and good value.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style=
"line-height: normal; text-align: right;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">Alistair Coull
    <br />
    Birmingham Post
    <br />
    August 20, 2004
    <br /></span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>