<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Sophisticated tourer with driver appeal A matter of
    opinion: Audi A6 2.5TDI SE Avant</span></strong>
</p>These days, everybody loves sports utilities. And with good
reason. They offer a commanding view, fantastic cargo space and
four wheel drive. But what they don&#39;t offer is precise
handling, decent fuel economy and easy manoeuvrability.
<br />
For those things, you have to look a little closer to the pavement
- at vehicles like Audi&#39;s A6 Avant, to me the perfect SUV
alternative.
<br />
The Avant, which was uprated last year, competes with estates and
sportwagons from Volvo, Mercedes Benz, Saab, BMW, Rover and, in the
not too distant future, from Jaguar. That&#39;s on top of rivalry
from the ever-popular SUVs. With as much as 1600 litres of cargo
space and standard quattro all-wheel-drive, the Audi has everything
those luxury SUVs have except the skyscraper views and the
mile-high fuel costs.
<br />
When I first set eyes on the Audi A6 Avant test car, I thought it
looked like something right out of Star Wars - with its shiny
silver bodywork, steeply raked rear window, creased edges and
inflated stance. OK for sci-fi films I thought, but not for a town
living family. As the week went on, however, the car&#39;s styling
grew on me more and more. The test car was powered by a 2.5-litre
V6 turbo diesel engine that developed 180bhp and 273 foot pounds of
torque. The engine was smooth and quiet, even when you floored the
accelerator and the Audi A6 took off like a rottweiler after a
bone. The Avant is a heavy car but it still managed the 0-62mph
dash in a shade over nine seconds. Top speed is 137mph when mated,
as in the test car, to a six-speed manual gearbox. There were a
couple of things that stood out immediately - precision and
privacy. I remember old estate cars and they weren&#39;t much fun
to drive as they wallowed all over the place. Luxury estates
hitting show rooms these days provide plenty of thrills and the
Audi A6 Avant is no exception.
<br />
You expect a car like the Audi to perform perfectly on the motorway
- and it does - but I was surprised how well it coped on the
twistier stuff in the Pennines. It cornered as easily at high speed
as it did at 30mph. Steering is perfect, the tyres surrounding the
16- inch alloys gripped well and I had bags of confidence in the
car&#39;s anti-lock brakes.
<br />
Those who value their privacy will appreciate the A6. It took only
one short trip to make me realise how quiet the Audi A6 was. I felt
I was in a soundproof cocoon gliding through the busy city centre.
On the open road, I passed juggernauts in silence. Wind, engine and
road noise seemed non-existent and there was never any need to
blast the radio to drown out traffic noise. The cabin was tightly
built as well - not once did I detect a creak, rattle or shimmy
from loose cabin materials.
<br />
Inside the cabin, you are greeted with a sea of red digital
readouts amid an, at first, baffling array of stereo and climate
control buttons enough to make your head swim. But study it for a
few minutes and it all makes perfect sense and is fairly easy to
use. There is ample room for five adults to travel in comfort and
there is still bags of luggage room. A floor net stops small items
rolling as round while a vertical net keeps larger items in check.
A cargo cover keeps it all out of sight of inquisitive eyes.
<br />
Standard equipment is comprehensive but includes traction control,
pollen filter, electronic brake force distribution with Brake
Assist, as well as front and side airbags.
<br />
Admitting to owning an estate car not that many years ago was
enough to exclude anyone from any serious dialogue about so-called
driving pleasure. An estate car - with practicality - well, okay,
but an estate and driving pleasure? Hardly. The two words were
chalk and cheese. Punters bought estates to lug around families,
business paraphernalia, dogs, cats, partly demented parakeets, half
a market garden - everything but the proverbial kitchen sink. They
were mini- removal vans with side windows and damn the comfort.
<br />
As for driving thrills, driving satisfaction ... Madam! this is not
a racing machine. Quite. But there was ample room for driving
enhancement and creature comforts and there have been huge strides
in turning estates, shooting brakes, tourers (some described them
as wind tunnels on wheels) into sophisticated machines that can and
do double up as all-round &#39;transporters&#39;, while providing
the all- important driving enjoyment, too. One of the leaders in
its field which easily qualifies for the sophisticate label, while
embracing the hurly, burly of 21st century living - and offering
driving satisfaction, if not exactly excitement - is Audi&#39;s A6
Avant 2.5TDi.
<br />
It is not the best Quattro on wheels in terms of the adrenalin
factor, yet it is thoroughly confidence-inspiring and lively enough
to kindle the blood - and it does so, smoothly and quietly,
achieving a 0-60mphsprint in a commendable 9 seconds.
<br />
It&#39;s not necessary to throw a car or an estate around to enjoy
driving it and if you do adopt this style with the Audi A6 Avant,
it won&#39;t reward you. That&#39;s not to say it doesn&#39;t
tenaciously hug the terrafirma when the going gets interesting - it
does, but the Avant can take on a jostling gait that can be
unsettling to all but the driver. Otherwise, it is an altogether
comfortable ride, with the generous-sized cabin ensuring that a
full gaggle of five adults don&#39;t feel as though they&#39;ve
been shoehorned in. The 135mph Avant test car belts out 180bhp
which gives you some idea of the hearty muscle the A6&#39;s
2.5-turbo diesel power unit is capable of flexing. It&#39;s not
rivetting, but there&#39;s plenty of mid-range power which makes it
lively enough to be interesting.
<br />
The six-gear box proved slick and smooth and the 370Nm torque from
the heart of the A6 ensures it is always a ready and willing
performer. All this and the German diesel returned some laudable
fuel figures, both in town and on the open road: on a mixed drive
the TDi easily manages between 35 and 40pmg. In terms of looks, the
Audi A6 Avant, especially in its silver metallic livery, looks
every bit the svelte trendsetter, and with items such as climate
control, airbags all round and alloy wheels, its an extremely
attractive package.
<br />
<br />
<div style="text-align: right;">
    Alistair Coull &amp; Val Jessop
    <br />
    Daily Post
    <br />
    January 10, 2003
    <br />
</div>]]></text>
</root>