<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
"EN-US">So light, it slinks without slurping</span></strong>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">In
    all the recent brouhaha about new Jaguars and new Range Rovers
    and other &quot;mould-breaking&quot; luxury cars, little has
    been written about fuel economy improvements. The simple reason
    for this is: there have been none.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Oh
    yes, there have been some gains in small- and medium-sized
    cars, and even in the executive sector (four-cylinder versions
    of the new Vauxhall Omega, for instance, are commendably
    abstemious). But at the top end, where flash badges and big
    engines and acres of interior room and leather and polished
    tree are all the rage, fuel economy has never been much of an
    issue.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Why? Because it does not sell cars. If you can afford
    to spend 30-grand or more on a car, then you can afford to pump
    in as much unleaded fuel as necessary.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">One of the reasons why cars in the luxury class
    continue to slurp as they slink along, is that they are so
    heavy. This is one of the things that makes the new Audi A8 so
    refreshing. It is much lighter than its rivals. (It is also
    beautifully sculpted - one of the most handsome luxury cars
    ever launched - which is probably a much greater sales
    card.)</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The Audi is light, because it is made from aluminium.
    And it is not only the outer panels that are aluminium: Land
    Rover has been using that trick for years. Rather, it is used
    for the sheet metal and the chassis. The chassis is a complex
    lattice-type frame on to which sheet aluminium panels are
    integrated, sharing the load bearing. Audi reckons body weight
    had been reduced by about 140kg compared with conventional
    steel. The basic Audi A8, for instance, weighs 1,500kg, about
    300kg less than the latest Jaguar saloon.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Less weight means lower fuel consumption - partly
    because smaller, more frugal engines can be used. The basic
    Audi A8 model, as tested, gets by with only a 2.8-litre V6 -
    very small for a car that is meant to do battle with 4.0-litre
    Jaguars. It is also pleasingly brisk, if no tearaway.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">But aluminium is expensive. Ask most rival car
    companies what they think of the Audi A8, and they will laud
    the company&#39;s technological boldness while predicting
    commercial suicide. Even Audi admits that, at present, the
    technology is only suitable for low-volume cars; it will be
    years before a Mondeo or a Cavalier could be made from anything
    other than steel.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The stance of the Audi A8 is superb. While Ford has
    gone to great lengths to make its controversial new Scorpio
    eye- catching, by styling an odd- looking grille and tail, Audi
    has made its new charge eye- catching by simply getting the
    basic proportions right. There is nothing gimmicky about the
    Audi A8, it is simply a singular piece of architecture.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The cabin is pretty good, too: roomy, beautifully
    finished and well appointed, although some of the switchgear is
    too small and fiddly. The boot is vast, and the lightweight lid
    opens completely upright, facilitating loading.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Sad to report, then, that as a driver&#39;s car the 2.8
    version of the Audi A8 is unexceptional. It goes well enough
    and uses fuel parsimoniously for so large and roomy a car. But
    it seems to me that Audi has put so much effort into getting
    its top-range flagship model right - the 4.2-litre V8 quattro -
    that it has rather forgotten about the bread-and-butter
    front-drive V6 - pounds 12,200 less and likely to outsell the
    quattro by four-to-one.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The quattro has four-wheel drive, which gives it superb
    handling and traction, and a special rear suspension to match.
    It is breathtakingly fast for so big a car, helped by the light
    weight, and has a peach of a gearbox - Porsche&#39;s Tiptronic
    automatic, which has a separate selection plane for manual
    shifting.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The basic V6 gets none of these goodies. Like all big
    front-drive cars, the handling balance is never quite right; it
    always feels nose-heavy. The auto shift is good but sometimes,
    such as entering a village after a cross-country dash, the
    &quot;thinking&quot; auto box will not keep up with your mood
    swings, and you will have a real jolt of a gear change. The V6
    engine is fine, smooth and fast enough, but when you drive the
    Audi V8 you soon realise what performance you are missing. It
    is also a little flaccid in the middle ranges compared with the
    brawniest competing six- cylinder engines.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Normally, it is better to buy the bottom car in the
    range. Flashier badges and bigger engines usually mean more
    profit for the maker and less value for you. But with the Audi
    A8, there is only one model to aim for: the pounds 46,699 V8
    quattro. It is probably the best luxury car in the world, as
    well as being the most advanced.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The Audi A8 2.8 V6, on the other hand, is an almost
    car. A technological tour de force on paper, it does not feel
    as special on the move. But it is economical.&nbsp;</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US"><span style=
    "font-weight: bold;">Specifications</span></span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Audi A8 2.8 pounds 34,499</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">V6
    engine, 2771cc, 174bhp. Four-speed automatic gearbox. Top speed
    140mph, 0-60mph in 10.0 seconds. Average fuel consumption
    26.7mpg.&nbsp;</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US"><span style=
    "font-weight: bold;">Comparisons</span></span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">BMW 730i, pounds 39,800.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Faster, better to drive, but very conservative to look
    at. Much pricier, and not worth the extra over the A8.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Jaguar XJ6 4.05, pounds 34,950.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Traditionally, rather than progressively, styled.
    Better ride and handling than the Audi, but not nearly as
    roomy. Faster, thirstier. Good value, and our choice in this
    price bracket.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Lexus GS300, pounds 31,950.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Little brother to the superb LS400 - and not nearly as
    good. Cannot compete in this company.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Mercedes-Benz S280, pounds 37,500 Vastly roomy, quiet,
    but rather a slug. Gawky looks. Beautifully built,
    though.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"></p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    Gavin Green
    <br />
    The Independent - London
    <br />
    November 26, 1994
    <br />
</div>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <br />
</p>]]></text>
</root>