<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style=
"margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; line-height: normal;"></p>
<h3>
    <span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;">
    Honda Odyssey EX</span>
</h3>
<br />
Last month, PM conducted a comparison test of the current crop of
minivans (see &quot;Family Trucksters,&quot; Nov. 1999, page 82).
On the one hand, they turned out to be pretty much alike: four
doors, plenty of room for kids and their belongings, proven
front-wheel- drive drive-trains, easy to run to the grocery or the
lumber yard. But on the other hand, they also proved to be fairly
different from one another. The winner of that test was Honda&#39;s
Odyssey. It won for all the reasons that we&#39;ve enjoyed the last
year with ours.
<br />
True to their Honda heritage, the V6 and four-speed automatic
transmission perform with world-class character: smooth, quiet,
with a touch more oomph than the competition. In other basic
features--noise level inside the cabin, space, comfort, convenience
of controls--Odyssey stands at least equal to the best of its
competitors.
<br />
But despite its winning ways and features, our long-term tester
showed a few niggling problems toward the end of the test. For one,
the keyless remote never worked right. We&#39;ve mentioned this
problem in earlier reports, and right up to the end of the test the
system was annoyingly balky.
<br />
We had a recalcitrant sliding passenger-side door that compounded
our confusion with the keyless remote. But that, as well as the a/c
that shut down when both front and rear units were running
simultaneously, was fixed under warranty.
<br />
Despite these irritations we think that this is one superb
execution of the minivan theme. And the foldaway third seat beats
the heck out of any removable third seat arrangement. If you take a
Chrysler van as the design benchmark, then the Odyssey beats the
current standard, with its double power sliding doors and rear
seat. It has to be noted also that our long-term test van was a
very early production unit and the more recently built Odyssey that
was used in our comparison test exhibited none of the glitches that
our long-termer did.
<br />
We&#39;ll miss our Odyssey. It&#39;s one nasty-looking minivan.
Unlike most, this minivan has a stance and real visual presence.
<br />
<br />
<h6>
    Test Summary: Honda Odyssey EX
</h6>
<br />
Report number: 4 Total miles driven: 15,606 Miles driven since last
report: 4210 Average fuel economy: 22.3 mpg Worst observed fuel
economy: 18.9 mpg Best observed fuel economy: 23.9 mpg
Maintenance/repair costs: None
<br />
<br />
<p class="MsoNormal" style=
"margin-bottom: 0.0001pt; line-height: normal; text-align: right;">
    <span style=
    "font-size: 12pt; font-family: &quot;Times New Roman&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;;">
    Popular Mechanics
    <br />
    December 1, 1999</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>