<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">2000 200 = 240; S2000 gets
    a bigger engine and more usable power.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">There are significant
    improvements to the 2004 Honda S2000, but you have to push a
    little to find them. Indeed, after several laps of the Spring
    Mountain Motorsports Park road course out in the desert near
    Las Vegas, we were searching our senses to notice.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Yes, there was more torque
    from the 200 new cubic centimeters of displacement added when
    the 2.0-liter normally aspirated four-cylinder engine was
    stroked. Yes, the car&#39;s rear felt better planted with its
    revised suspension tuning and 17-inch wheels and meatier
    Bridgestone RE 050 tires-215/45 front, 245/40 rears. And yes,
    the new transmission ratios and better shifter feel were
    evident, too. There was even more room in the cockpit than
    before-a half-inch more hip and shoulder room. But was that
    all?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&quot;Ask Mr. Uehara, the
    chief engineer, to take you out for a couple laps,&#39;&#39;
    said a Honda guy.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Uehara? That was a familiar
    name. Where had we heard it? We asked Uehara-san if he was
    available for a tour of the track. He bowed humbly showing much
    reserve. We asked several times, not sure if he understood what
    we wanted. The translator said he had agreed, and the engineers
    who seemed to be hovering around him like novices said he had
    agreed. But it was a few, somewhat awkward minutes before we
    actually got in the car. Why had the Honda guy suggested
    this?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Then, oh man: Uehara nailed
    the throttle and wailed up through the gears, smacking redline
    in each one like he designed the whole thing.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&quot;More
    torque,&#39;&#39; was all he said.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">He entered the very first
    turn, a long right-hand constant-radius sweeper, at what seemed
    like about 20 mph faster than we had been driving through it
    all morning-faster than anyone had ever driven through the
    thing ever for all we could guess. Who knew the S2000 could go
    this fast?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Then, in mid-turn, at what
    we had assumed was the limit of adhesion, Uehara lifted off the
    throttle and sawed the wheel back and forth a few times.
    Despite the new revised spring, damper and antiroll bar rates,
    increased body rigidity, enhanced suspension bushings and
    optimized rear toe settings, we expected to swap ends and start
    bouncing backward across the gravel runoff area, dust and rocks
    flying, lizards leaping, jack rabbits fleeing for their lives.
    But no, the S2000 just kept on gripping the hot
    pavement.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&quot;Revised suspension
    means better control of lift-throttle oversteer,&#39;&#39; he
    said.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Then we remembered: Uehara
    was Uehara, the father of the S2000, the father of the NSX and
    the former chief engineer of the Honda F1 efforts.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">He kept it up for three
    more laps, doing a magnificent job of heel-and-toe downshifting
    into each turn, nailing the throttle on the way out and making
    the S2000 yelp with pleasure.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">When we pulled back into
    the paddock, &quot;Thank you,&#39;&#39; was all he said.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">No, thank you, we said. We
    had seen the light. We were ready to snatch the pebble from his
    hand. We got back into another 2004 S2000 and had at it. Yes,
    it goes quicker than we had assumed. Yes, it has more torque.
    Yes, it shifts better. So, this was how you&#39;re supposed to
    drive this thing!</span>
</p><span style=
"font-size: 11pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: &quot;Calibri&quot;,&quot;sans-serif&quot;;"
lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">We stayed out all day, trying to take
all the tread off all the cars. It was great.
<br />
<br /></span>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Vaughan, Mark</span>
    <br />
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">AutoWeek</span>
    <br />
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">October 6, 2003</span>
</div>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>]]></text>
</root>