<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Volvo S60 in ways is
    mini-S80 model.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Think of the S60 as a
    scaled-down version of Volvo&#39;s flagship S80 model. Not
    exactly a Mini-Me of the S80 (the S80 is 10 inches longer, 1
    inch wider and 1 inch taller than the S60), the S60 shares a
    modified version of its platform and many of its
    mechanicals.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The manufacturer&#39;s
    suggested retail price of the entry-level S60 is about $10,000
    less than that of the S80, too. In other words, if you like the
    S80, you probably will feel the same about its smaller
    sibling.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A new model, the S60
    replaces the squarish and dated S70 in Volvo&#39;s lineup. This
    Swedish manufacturer has a showroom stuffed with svelte sedans,
    coupes, wagons and convertibles. The new S60 looks right at
    home among Volvo&#39;s more stylized entries. The sloping roof
    line of the S60, a sedan, almost gives it the appearance of a
    coupe. Its well-defined belt line begins at the front of the
    hood and continues unhindered to the tip of the trunk lid. This
    is a beautiful design, shocking many a passer-by into asking if
    it really is a Volvo. It has nary a right angle or straight
    line anywhere on it.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Volvo traditionally has
    claimed the safety high ground. Its current crop of vehicles
    doesn&#39;t deviate from its safety heritage; however,
    performance now is as important an element of a Volvo&#39;s
    equation as safety.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Three five-cylinder engines
    with varying degrees of vigor power the S60. A normally
    aspirated 2.4-liter is good for 168 horsepower, while a light
    turbocharged version of the 2.4 bumps up the heat to 197
    horsepower. The most powerful of the trio is a 247-horsepower
    2.3-liter turbocharged engine. The 2.4 and 2.3 T can be fitted
    with either a five-speed manual or a five-speed automatic. The
    2.4T is available with only the five-speed automatic.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The test Volvo was the
    high-performance S60 T5. This is Volvo-speak for the 2.3T
    engine. The five-speed manual transmission passed my 2.3T&#39;s
    output to the front wheels.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">If you think the S60&#39;s
    exterior styling is a departure from Volvos of old, wait until
    you get a load of its performance. Putting a foot on the
    accelerator is rewarded with an immediate burst of energy. The
    turbo spools up instantly. Going from zero to 60 mph can take
    less than seven seconds.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The shifter works smoothly,
    adding to the fun. Fuel economy is decent, too, with an
    Environmental Protection Agency rating of 21 mpg in town and 28
    mpg on the highway.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Handling is crisp and
    predictable. Sticky 17-inch tires nearly lock the S60 to the
    pavement. It goes where it is pointed. The steering offers just
    the right amount of resistance. Although the ride differs among
    the three models from the softer experience of the entry-level
    version to the performance-tuned architecture of the T5,
    passenger comfort is not a trade-off for sharp handling. The
    fully independent suspension absorbs imperfections in the
    pavement without disturbing the passenger compartment, yet the
    S60 retains its composure when flung into a turn.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Loaded with safety
    features, the S60 won&#39;t disappoint the &quot;Baby on
    Board&quot; set. Front side-impact air bags are supplemented by
    Volvo&#39;s Inflatable Curtain Side Impact Head Protection
    System. A Whiplash Protection System is built into the front
    seats to absorb the forces of a rear-end collision. All five
    three-point seat belts feature height adjustment and
    pretensioners.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Although well constructed,
    the interior is simple and uncluttered. There is no pushing of
    the styling envelope inside the cabin. Everything is close at
    hand and easy to use. The gauges are easy to decipher as well.
    Seating is comfortable and engineered for fatigue-free touring.
    A decent-size trunk with a low lift-over also encourages
    cross-country excursions.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">At $31,800, the S60 T5 is
    reasonably priced. It competes with the likes of the Audi A6
    and Acura TL. Offering sensible engine choices, uncompromising
    safety, a fetching exterior and European-style handling, the
    S60 can go toe to toe with any sedan in its segment.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Other standard features not
    already mentioned: eight-way power front seats,
    tilt/telescoping steering wheel, remote keyless entry, power
    windows and door locks, cruise control, dual-power heated
    outboard mirrors, trip computer and dual-zone automatic climate
    control. Leather seats are a $1,300 option. The $450 Cold
    Weather Touring Package adds security side glass, memory
    mirrors and electric foldable rear headrests.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The test S60 T5 had $5,200
    worth of options in all. With the $575 delivery charge, the
    total price came to $37,575.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Heaps, Russ</span>
    <br />
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The Washington Times</span>
    <br />
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">March 16, 2001</span>
    <br />
</div>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&nbsp;</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>