<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Motoring: Volvo V50 prays
    for a cold snap.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US"><br />
    It was eight in the morning but it was still pitch dark.
    Outside, the snow was coming at us horizontally, blown by
    strong northerly winds.
    <br />
    <br />
    The temperature gauge on the dashboard of Volvo&#39;s new V50
    AWD said it was minus 8C - warm for early February 150 miles
    inside the Arctic Circle.
    <br />
    <br />
    Ahead of us lay a route that would take us to almost within
    touching distance of the Russian border. If we could get
    through the three-kilometrewide exclusion zone, avoid being
    seen from the watch towers sited on nearby hills, all that lay
    between us andthe remnants of the Russian Navy&#39;s Northern
    Fleet at anchor in Murmansk was just under 200 miles of pine
    forest buried in winter snow.
    <br />
    <br />
    This was Volvo&#39;s Winter Challenge - to pit machine against
    everything a harsh Scandinavian winter could throw at it.
    <br />
    <br />
    We were based near Ivalo and a town perhaps best known as the
    home of Santa Claus to hundreds of children taken there by
    their parents to visit him in his workshop in the weeks running
    up to Christmas.
    <br />
    <br />
    On test were a V8 powered version of Volvo&#39;s best-selling
    XC90 SUV and an all-wheeldrive derivative of the V50 estate
    car.
    <br />
    <br />
    Available in left-hand drive only, there are no plans tobring
    the XC90 V8 to the UK. But at least it gave you a good
    indication of the 4x4 capability and agility of its
    smallerengined siblings, as well as the V50 AWD, on frozen
    routes as hard as graniteor on softer ploughed, knee deep snow.
    <br />
    <br />
    Technical difficulties in fitting the transverse-mounted engine
    stop the Swedes from making the car into a righthand drive
    model. It will do well in its main US market, however, where an
    average fuel consumption of just under 21mpg will not deter
    buyersstill paying only pounds 1 a gallon.
    <br />
    <br />
    The V50 AWD will go on sale in the UK, however, where I reckon
    it will do well against its rivals, the Jaguar X-Type Estate,
    the Audi A4 Avant quattro and BMW 3-Series Touring.
    <br />
    <br />
    Available in Sport, SE and SE Sport trim levels, prices range
    from pounds 25,513 to pounds 27,363 on the road.
    <br />
    <br />
    Power comes from a strong T5, five-cylinder 2.5-litre petrol
    engine with a light-pressure turbo which produces exceptional
    torque. The high, flat torque curve ensures great acceleration
    with 320Nm of torque available all the way from 1,500 to
    4,800rpm -with a maximum output of220bhp. Acceleration from
    rest to 62mph takes only 7.2 seconds and top speed is 143mph
    (140mph auto).
    <br />
    <br />
    The all-wheel-drive is the same Haldex system already fitted to
    Volvo&#39;s larger AWD models - the V70, XC70 and XC90.
    <br />
    <br />
    Engine power is automatically distributed between the front and
    rear wheels with the help of an extremely fastresponding
    electricallyoperated hydraulic clutch which transmits maximum
    torque to the rear wheels even before the front wheels have
    rotated aquarter of a revolution.
    <br />
    <br />
    This instant engagement and disengagement continues for
    consistent and stable road manners on all types of surface. In
    Finland, that meant ice and snow as well as snow-ploughed
    tarmac. Stability is boosted by theAWD system&#39;s extra
    weight over the rearwheels.
    <br />
    <br />
    On a test track shared with half a dozen rally-prepared Subaru
    Imprezas, the V50 AWD showed just what it could do.
    <br />
    <br />
    On the handling track carved out of hard-packed snow, and full
    of tricky corners, the rear of the car would start to break
    away but a correction on the steering wheel would bring it back
    into line.
    <br />
    <br />
    The independent all-round suspension has spring struts at the
    front and a multi-link system at the rear which provides a
    certain degree of passive steering - helping to counteract any
    skid.
    <br />
    <br />
    The car was equally impressive on a slalom. Keep a steady
    pressure on the accelerator and the car behaves as if it is
    stuck with glue.
    <br />
    <br />
    Only when the driver forgets to be gentle with the throttle
    does the V50 show any tendency to send the back end out of
    line.
    <br />
    <br />
    Accelerating hard in a straight line on the iceand slamming on
    the brakes should, you might think, send the car spinning all
    over the ice. It didn&#39;t. The car stayed true and never
    wavered.
    <br />
    <br />
    The V50 isfitted with very powerful ABS brakes - with
    electronic brake force distribution to the rear wheels and
    automatic panic braking assistance - EBA (Energy Braking
    Assistance), plus Volvo&#39;s advanced DSTC (Dynamic Stability
    and Traction Control) asstandard.
    <br />
    <br />
    The DSTC system automatically counteracts a skid as it starts
    by activating the brakes and/or reducing engine torque to help
    maintain driving control. However it does it, it works.
    <br />
    <br />
    The return leg to Ivalo and a well-earned sauna included a
    50-mile adventure along narrow, snow-smothered forest tracks.
    <br />
    <br />
    In places, it was almost impossible to see where you had to go.
    Only the piles of snow at the side of the track where they had
    been pushed by a snowplough days, maybe weeks before indicated
    the way ahead.
    <br />
    <br />
    A sudden twitch at the rear as the car found a hidden rut or
    icy patch was soon rectified by a responsive tug at the wheel.
    <br />
    <br />
    Mistakes could be made. One car did get stuck and had to be
    pulled free after misreading a soft verge for the track, but
    that was driver error. The car itself behaved impeccably. It
    was an impressive display of how the V50 can cope with
    conditions farmore severe than anything Britain is ever likely
    to see.
    <br />
    <br />
    Just what the doctor ordered, then, in this week&#39;s snow and
    ice</span>
</p>
<p style="text-align: right;" class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Alistair Coull
    <br />
    Birmingham Post
    <br />
    February 25, 2005&nbsp;</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>