<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h3>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Subaru in new neighborhood
    with Tribeca.</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Subaru dubbed its 2006
    crossover the Tribeca for a section in the Big Apple where
    actor Robert DeNiro hangs his hat and which has become the
    neighborhood du jour of budding designers as well as the
    &quot;hip&quot; and &quot;cool&quot; and wannabes.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Why name a new vehicle
    Tribeca when some will end up calling it Trifecta?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">So folks who slip behind
    the wheel of one will consider it a hip and cool crossover,
    Subaru says.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Subaru calls Tribeca
    &quot;progressively designed,&quot; which must be the way the
    hip and cool describe &quot;odd.&quot;</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Despite the logo in the
    grille, this machine doesn&#39;t look like a Subaru, but rather
    a crossover with a large sloping nose with a huge chrome grille
    and sharply curved sheet metal.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Several stopped to ask what
    it was and nearly all expressed surprise when told a Subaru. It
    leads us to believe that if folks can&#39;t tell what it is,
    Subaru should have used its marketing research dollars more
    wisely.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Inside, the dash top is
    large for the feeling of plenty of space between you and
    anything upfront in the event of an impact. But unless
    you&#39;re taller than 6 feet, you probably won&#39;t see the
    hood over that large dash when parking.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Subaru added a new flagship
    model because when loyalists need more room for passengers or
    cargo, they shop sport-utility vehicles and minivans from its
    rivals.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Tribeca is meant to stop
    the exodus and ensure Subaru rings up 30,000 sales it otherwise
    would have lost each year.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Tribeca (actually, the name
    is even worse, it&#39;s the B9 Tribeca, with B standing for the
    6-cylinder Boxer engine and 9 standing for the model series),
    is derived from a stretch of the platform used to produce the
    Outback.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Tribeca is built on a
    3-inch-longer wheelbase and is about 1 inch longer, 3 inches
    wider and 7 inches higher than Outback.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">It comes in regular and
    Limited editions. The latter has leather seats in a choice of
    five-passenger capacity in two rows or, for the first time at
    Subaru, seven passengers in three.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Regardless of the number of
    seats, all Tribecas have full-time all-wheel-drive, long noted
    as the common DNA among Subarus.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">We tested the
    seven-passenger Limited. The nice thing about the seats is that
    the second row slides forward or back by up to 8 inches to give
    occupants even more legroom.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The problem, however, is
    that even with the second seat being moved, third-row occupants
    are hard-pressed to find space for legs and/or feet. Third row
    is the designated home for kids and looks as if it was
    shoehorned into the cabin. Rather than stretching the Outback
    platform by only 1 inch, Subaru should have kept extending it
    to allow ample room for a third row.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Another problem is getting
    into the third row. The second-row seat behind the passenger
    has a lever to pull so the seat back folds and the seat bottom
    slides forward. But even when it does, there&#39;s precious
    little aisle space. And it&#39;s even worse trying to get
    out.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A great party game would be
    to have an adult guest get into and out of the third row
    without help in less than, say, an hour.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">When third-row seats are
    vacant, the backs fold flat to expand cargo space. Second-row
    seat backs fold flat as well to create a spacious cargo hold.
    Second- and third-row seat backs split so you can lower only
    one side if you want. When the third-row seats are full,
    however, you have very little room behind to slip anything
    other than a couple of small duffel bags.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The test vehicle came with
    optional DVD player, fold-down screen and headphones to serve
    second and third rows.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Nice touches include a pair
    of power plugs in the center console and a pair of cell-phone
    holders directly in front of those plugs alongside a pair of
    cupholders. There&#39;s also a power plug along the side wall
    for third-seat occupants, perhaps so they can call for help
    when their legs fall asleep from being scrunched.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">When you lift the floor
    cover in the cargo hold, there are a few holders to keep odds
    and ends hidden.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The neatest feature is the
    navigation screen, not for its maps, but for its bonus goodies.
    One is a calculator you can call up on the screen to add,
    subtract, multiply or divide _ whether in raw numbers or in
    inches, feet, acres, gallons or pounds. Strike another button
    and a calendar pops up. How often would you need a calculator
    or calendar? Probably more often than you would a map to show
    you the way home 50 weeks a year.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Tribeca is powered by a
    3-liter, 250-horsepower 6-cylinder engine with 5-speed
    automatic transmission that provides ample off-the-line power,
    though with a slight growl. The mileage rating is only 18
    m.p.g. city/23 m.p.g. highway, the result, in part, of
    full-time all-wheel-drive.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">While the 6-cylinder
    growled a bit, Tribeca had an unusually smooth and quiet ride.
    Imperfections in the road didn&#39;t give it the
    jitters.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">When it comes to handling,
    however, expect the body to lean a little in sharp corners and
    turns. But the standard stability/traction control systems
    along with AWD provide a sense of security for all-season and
    all-reason motoring.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">While some motorists opt
    for all-wheel-drive just to have it, Subaru says its customers
    favor AWD because their lifestyles require it to get to the ski
    lodge or cabin. There is no AWD low, however, so you have to
    get to the cabin via the paved road rather than by climbing the
    boulders off the beaten path.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">The five-passenger Tribeca
    starts at $30,695, the seven-passenger at $32,395. The
    five-passenger Limited starts at $32,295, the seven-passenger
    Limited we tested at $33,895. Limited models add leather seats
    and an audio upgrade with CD players.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Only options on the Limited
    are the DVD entertainment and the navigation systems.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Standard equipment includes
    anti-lock brakes; front/side air bags and side-curtain air
    bags; AM/FM stereo with CD player; air conditioning; power
    front seats; power heated mirrors; 18-inch, all-season, radial
    tires; tilt steering; and cruise control.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Tribeca is built at
    Subaru&#39;s plant in Lafayette, Ind. Saab will get a version
    later this year or early next, as a companion to its new 9-7X
    sport-utility vehicle. General Motors owns Saab and a 20
    percent equity interest in Fuji Heavy Industries, parent of
    Subaru, and sharing derivatives is an inexpensive way for the
    lower-volume GM affiliates to expand limited lineups.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">___</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<h6>
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">2006 Subaru B9 Tribeca
    AWD</span>
</h6>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Wheelbase: 108.2
    inches</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Length: 189.8 inches</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Engine: 3-liter, 250-h.p.
    6-cylinder</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Transmission: 5-speed
    automatic with manual mode</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Fuel economy: 18 m.p.g.
    city/23 m.p.g. highway</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Base price: $33,895</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Price as tested: $37,695.
    Includes $1,800 for DVD entertainment system and $2,000 for
    navigation system. Add $625 for freight.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Pluses: Bigger Subaru
    derived from Outback. It offers seating for seven, full-time
    all-wheel-drive, quiet ride, decent storage and a
    calculator/calendar in navi screen.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Minuses: Getting into or
    out of third-row seat and minuscule third-row legroom.
    What&#39;s left of cargo hold when the third-row seat is being
    used is small. A $34,000 Subaru?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">___</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Q. Your article on Mark
    LaNeve of General Motors was interesting. You mention
    &quot;There&#39;s no question that much of GM&#39;s problem can
    be traced to massive health-care expenses that add $1,500 to
    the cost of each vehicle it builds.&quot; This may be true, but
    the problem with their health-care costs is not a problem
    caused by their poor products; rather, it is a symptom of our
    poor health-care system. It&#39;s scary to see this given as a
    reason for an impact on sales. If their products were in
    demand, health-care costs would mean nothing. GM has nothing to
    offer the average American. I haven&#39;t been interested in a
    GM car since the `70s and couldn&#39;t name a product I&#39;d
    buy today that GM produces.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">_G.T., Chicago</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A. The $1,500 added to the
    price of each vehicle to cover health-care costs is one reason
    GM reported lower profits in the first quarter of this year, it
    wasn&#39;t given as the reason for lower vehicle sales. One
    reason for lower vehicle sales, of course, is your 35-year
    dislike of GM products.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">If GM&#39;s products were
    in demand, health care would still be an issue, only the more
    vehicles it sold, the more units it could spread its
    health-care costs over, thus lowering the tab.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Q. I don&#39;t understand
    it. For years Ford has been trying to come up with a car to
    compete with Toyota&#39;s Camry and Honda&#39;s Accord and
    recapture the No. 1 sales spot. The Five Hundred appears to be
    a winner in every way. It looks better inside and out compared
    to the imports. The quality, at least the perception of
    quality, appears to be as good, and the price is competitive.
    In addition, the Five Hundred offers all-wheel-drive. Yet with
    all that is good, the press, including you, fail to salute Ford
    for making a car that far exceeds anything from
    overseas.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Given a choice between the
    two boring and homogeneous imports and the Five Hundred, this
    Ford is my first choice.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">_C.S., Chicago</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A. Don&#39;t know about a
    salute, but we&#39;ve pointed out that the Five Hundred is a
    fine car and one of our few objections is that it needs a
    little more potent engine. We&#39;ve also noted that
    all-wheel-drive is a feature the Japanese competition lacks in
    its cars _ for now _ just like hybrid power is a feature Ford
    lacks in its cars for now.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Q. I can&#39;t help but
    feel you are wrong about the future popularity of hybrid cars.
    It&#39;s possible to have a car that will get hundreds of miles
    per gallon of gas once a car gets rolling and the battery takes
    over. People are ready for hybrids to break the petrol
    industry&#39;s stranglehold on the U.S.A. I want to buy the
    future. I&#39;ve lived long enough in the past.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">_J.M., Tinley Park,
    Ill.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A. Our feeling about
    gas/electric cars is that they make lots of sense in terms of
    saving gas and reducing pollution but have to be sold in far
    greater numbers than they are now to have a major effect on the
    dependence on foreign oil and pollution levels. Hybrids
    won&#39;t eliminate petroleum, because they also use
    gas.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Q. Does Mazda have any
    plans to release a turbocharged version of the RX-8 anytime
    soon? Also how long does Mazda plan on keeping the RX-8 in
    production?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">_J.L., Chicago</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A. Mazda spokesman Jeremy
    Barnes said a turbocharged RX-8 isn&#39;t in the
    automaker&#39;s immediate plans. The RX-8, however, &quot;is a
    key part of our future plans and we have no plans to
    discontinue it or the rotary engine. When the rotary first came
    out in the U.S., there were emissions problems, but those are
    problems of the past.&quot;</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Q. I&#39;m interested in
    purchasing the Lexus SC430 but I&#39;ve heard from a neighbor
    that the 2006 will be converted to all-wheel-drive. The
    salespeople I&#39;ve talked to say only &quot;maybe.&quot; Will
    it or won&#39;t it be all-wheel-drive?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">_R.M., St. John,
    Ind.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">A. It won&#39;t be. Lexus
    offers the 2006 AWD GS300 now and will offer the AWD IS250 this
    fall, but the only changes coming on the SC430 this fall are a
    new 6-speed automatic transmission, adaptive lighting (the
    headlamps move in the direction of a turn) and some minor
    interior and exterior upgrades.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">___</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">(Send questions about cars
    and trucks to Jim Mateja, Chicago Tribune, 616 Atrium Drive,
    Vernon Hills, IL 60061-1523, or send e-mail, including name and
    hometown, to jmateja@tribune.com.)</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">___</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">(c) 2005, Chicago
    Tribune.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Visit the Chicago Tribune
    on the Internet at http://www.chicagotribune.com/</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Distributed by Knight
    Ridder/Tribune Information Services.</span>
</p>
<p style="text-align: right;" class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Mateja, Jim
    <br />
    Chicago Tribune (Chicago, IL)
    <br />
    June 3, 2005</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
    <span lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">&nbsp;</span>
</p>]]></text>
</root>