<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<text><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <strong><span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Avalon is big American in every way except for the
    Toyota name.</span></strong>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">Is
    it a full-size premium sedan? Is it a near-luxury sedan? Is it
    a domestic sedan, and if so, is it better slotted in against
    Buicks, Oldsmobiles and Chryslers, than imports?</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">These are legitimate questions raised when debating the
    Toyota Avalon. It is such an anomaly within the traditional
    Toyota stable that trying to pigeonhole or define it can be
    challenging.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The 2000 Toyota Avalon is the second generation of this
    disturbingly American sedan. With the car constructed
    exclusively in Kentucky, it can be argued that Avalon is
    American, if not a bona fide domestic. Its American
    credentials, however, don&#39;t end with its build site.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">This is a large sedan engineered to butt heads with
    traditional American fare such as the Chrysler LHS, Buick
    LeSabre and yes, even the Ford Crown Victoria. When has an
    Asian manufacturer ever tried that? It is sort of plain on the
    outside, huge inside and has a truly boulevard ride. If you
    didn&#39;t know up front that Avalon was a Toyota, it probably
    wouldn&#39;t be your first, second or even third guess. This is
    a very American sedan in nearly every sense of the word.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">While the styling has moved forward, the redesigned
    Avalon is very similar in size to its predecessor. Its length
    and wheelbase are unchanged. Both its height and width have
    been expanded by about an inch. Although it is wider and
    taller, Avalon&#39;s coefficient of drag has been reduced from
    0.31 to 0.28. There is extra space inside too, but it is the
    rear seat passengers who have really benefited. There is
    substantially more legroom (2 inches) for rear seat passengers.
    However, front seat occupants find their legroom reduced by
    about the same amount.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Reallocating this space hasn&#39;t noticeably affected
    front-seat comfort but has done much to improve the quality of
    life in the rear. Because the seats have been raised a bit for
    improved visibility, the added exterior height doesn&#39;t
    translate into increased headroom. The extra width does offer
    more shoulder room. In other words, this was a spacious
    interior before and it has even more room now.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Powering Toyota Avalon is the same 3-liter V-6 found in
    the Lexus ES 300. In the Toyota Avalon it produces 210
    horsepower and 220 foot-pounds of peak torque. Toyota has a
    reputation for building quiet, efficient, smooth-running power
    plants and the 3.0 V-6 is no exception.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">While it doesn&#39;t blast off the line, it gathers
    itself up rather quickly and has plenty of reserve for
    higher-speed passing. A buttery four-speed automatic
    transmission conveys engine output to the front wheels.
    Reaching 60 mph from a standstill takes between eight and nine
    seconds. Fuel economy is about average for a V-6 in this weight
    class with a rating of 21 in the city and 29 on the
    highway.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Toyota Avalon rides atop a fully independent
    suspension. Although some cornering crispness has been
    sacrificed for the remarkably pleasant ride, steering response
    is immediate. Disc brakes on all four corners rein in the
    Toyota Avalon. Anti-lock brakes are standard.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Highlights of the interior are the wonderfully
    supportive seats, a variety of storage cubbies and the
    user-friendly instrument panel. The dashboard has been moved
    forward a few inches, creating a more spacious feeling. This is
    a more interesting interior when configured for five passengers
    than six. The shifter moves from the steering column to the
    center console, and the front seats become buckets rather than
    a bench.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Placed above the ventilation system controls, the audio
    controls are simple to operate. A rather large blue screen
    dominates the top center of the dashboard, providing everything
    from the time and date to how many miles worth of fuel remains.
    The trunk is large and will ingest a volume of cargo.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">Quietness is also a Toyota trademark, and Avalon is
    certainly that. In fact, from inside Avalon&#39;s cabin you may
    be hard pressed to distinguish this sedan from its upscale
    Lexus brethren.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang=
    "EN-US">The base price of the Toyota Avalon XLS is $29,755 (the
    XL retails for $25,195). Standard features not already
    mentioned include dual front air bags, dual front side-impact
    air bags, height-adjustable front shoulder belts, daytime
    running lamps, dual-power outboard mirrors, 16-inch alloy
    wheels, cruise control, an information center, an outside
    temperature gauge, variable intermittent wipers, a
    seven-speaker JBL AM-FM stereo cassette-CD player, dual-zone
    automatic climate control, a leather-wrapped tilt steering
    wheel, power windows and door locks, keyless remote entry and
    auto on-off headlamps.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" lang="EN-US" xml:lang="EN-US">My
    test Toyota Avalon XLS also had power moonroof ($910), vehicle
    stability control ($850), and the leather package ($1,625) with
    leather seats, upgraded JBL audio system with six-disc in-dash
    CD changer, memory for driver&#39;s seat and outboard mirrors,
    and upgraded wheels. Adding the $485 delivery charge brought
    the price as tested to $33,625.</span>
    <br />
</p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    Heaps, Russ
    <br />
    The Washington Times
    <br />
    March 3, 2000
    <br />
</div>
<br />]]></text>
</root>