<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<desc><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"></p>
<h3>
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;">Destroyed Bentleys the stuff of
    legend</span>
</h3>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Among the Bentleys destroyed in yesterday&#39;s fire is
    the oldest surviving Bentley (chassis number 5, engine number
    1), a 3-litre <span style="">car</span> built in September 1921
    and used by Bentley as a demonstrator to sell one of the
    greatest all motoring breeds to the rich and racey.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">The other machines undergoing restoration, rebuilding
    or simply being stored at Excel Engineering - an expert Bentley
    restoration outfit - date from between 1922 and 1931. Among
    them is YV9987, a 1927 4 1/2 -litre tourer: its distraught
    owner had brought it back to Solihull on Sunday for a 500-mile
    service after a complete restoration.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Vintage Bentleys are not just valuable, but the stuff
    of motoring legend on and off the track. These are the great
    Bulldog Drummond breed of green and black Bentleys that won the
    famous Le Mans 24-hour race five times for Britain, beating
    contemporary Bugattis and Alfa-Romeos. Ettorre Bugatti, in a
    famous quip, described the 35-cwt racer as the
    &quot;world&#39;s fastest lorry&quot;.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Small wonder Jim Pike and Graham King, joint owners of
    Excel Engineering, risked severe injury in an ill-fated attempt
    to save the cars. These were not just any Bentleys, but the
    real thing: magnificent high-speed machines designed and built
    by one of the greatest of all British engineers W. O. Bentley
    (1889-1971) during the all too brief 12-year history of his
    headline-snatching, yet chronically underfunded manufacturing
    company.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Bentley Motors went bust during the Great Slump and was
    snatched up by its British rival Rolls-Royce. Rolls-Royce began
    making its own Bentleys in 1933, but the cars were softer,
    smoother and altogether less sporting than W O&#39;s automotive
    adrenalin pumps.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Rarity, racing pedigree and the sheer quality of the
    engineering that went into their construction have made vintage
    Bentleys some of the most valuable and sought after of all
    cars.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">The legendary 4 1/2 -litre supercharged Bentleys are
    worth about pounds 1m today.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Launched in the teeth of the 1929 slump, this model was
    priced originally at pounds 1,720.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">But Bentley dealers were forced to sell the last 50
    cars for as little as pounds 950 as buyers for such luxury
    machines faced bankruptcy. As late as the early Sixties it was
    possible to buy one of these 110mph Twenties&#39; supercars for
    well under pounds 600. Since then, prices have shot into the
    stratosphere.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <span style="font-size: 12pt;" xml:lang="EN-US" lang=
    "EN-US">Real Bentleys are rare because Bentley Motors went
    bankrupt because it built cars to a standard way above the
    ceiling of the company&#39;s finances.</span>
</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"></p>
<div style="text-align: right;">
    Jonathan Glancey
    <br />
    The Independent - London
    <br />
    March 8, 1994
    <br />
</div>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;">
    <br />
</p>]]></desc>
</root>