<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<desc><![CDATA[1948. Soichiro Honda incorporates Honda Technical Research
Institute and renames it Honda Motor Co., Ltd., capitalized at one
million yen.<br />
<br />
1963. Honda markets first automobile S500 and lightweight truck
T360 in Japan.<br />
<br />
1970. Honda exports N600 automobile to U.S.<br />
<br />
1979. Honda introduces the 4-door Accord sedan.<br />
<br />
1982. Car and Driver magazine names the Honda Accord to its list of
the Ten Best Cars for the first time.<br />
<br />
1985. The Honda Accord/Vigor series receive the 1985-86 Japan Car
of the Year Award.<br />
<br />
1990. American Honda becomes first automaker with plans to offer
standard driver and passenger airbags in all (Honda and Acura)
models by the 1994 model year.<br />
<br />
1991. The Honda Civic receives the 1991-92 Japan Car of the Year
Award.<br />
<br />
1992. Honda of America Mfg. builds its two-millionth automobile in
Ohio.<br />
<br />
1992. Honda Motor Co., Ltd. produces 20-millionth automobile in
Japan.<br />
<br />
1993. Honda of America Mfg., Inc. produces its three-millionth car
since beginning U.S. operations in 1982.<br />
<br />
1993. Honda of Canada Mfg., Inc. in Alliston, Ontario, produces the
500,000th automobile in its history, a Civic Hatchback.<br />
<br />
1994. American Honda Motor Co., Inc. surpasses 10 million
Honda/Acura automobile sales in the U.S.<br />
<br />
1994. American Honda exports its 100,000th U.S.-made vehicle for
the year, making the Honda Accord the No. 1 export model from North
America in 1994.<br />
<br />
1995. Automobile Magazine names the Honda Civic the 1996 Automobile
of the Year.<br />
<br />
1995. The Honda Civic receives the 1995-96 Japan Car of the Year
Award.<br />
<br />
1995. Honda Motor Co., Ltd. produces the 10 millionth Honda
Civic.<br />
<br />
1998. American Honda passes the 1 million mark in annual sales of
Honda and Acura cars and light trucks for the first time in company
history.<br />
<br />
2000. Civic Coupe achieves 5-star ratings for both frontal and side
impact tests by NHTSA and a "good" rating for offset barrier crash
tests by IIHS.<br />
<br />
2001. Fit earns the 2001-2002 Japan Car of the Year Award.<br />
<br />
2001. Honda Accord recaptures the best selling car title in the
U.S. in 2001.<br />
<br />
2002. Japan version of all-new Accord earns the 2002-03 Japan Car
of the Year Award - 3rd straight year a Honda model earned the
award.<br />
<br />
2002. Honda Fit series finishes 2002 as best-selling car in Japan,
a first for Honda. Fit also goes on sale in Europe as "Jazz"
model.<br />
<br />
2003. Worldwide cumulative production of Civic series reaches 15
million units.<br />
<br />
2003. Honda's cumulative worldwide production of automobiles
reaches 50 million units.<br />
<br />
2003. American Honda achieves 20 million cumulative automobile
sales in America, as well as 50 million for the total number of
Honda products (auto, motorcycle and power equipment) delivered to
American customers since the start of operations in September
1959.<br />
<br />
2004. All new Legend wins the Japan Car of the Year Award for
2004-2005 and Most Advanced Technology Award.<br />
<br />
2005. Honda Civic named 2006 Motor Trend Car of the Year.<br />
<br />
2005. Honda Ridgeline truck named 2006 Motor Trend Truck of the
Year.<br />
<br />
2006. Honda Civic and Ridgeline sweep North American Car and Truck
of the Year awards.<br />
<br />
2006. 2006 Civic and Ridgeline capture Canadian Car and Truck of
the Year Awards from Automotive Journalist Association of Canada
(AJAC).<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />]]></desc>
</root>