<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<body><![CDATA[<p>
    Porsche&#39;s new convertible roadster, the Boxster, is priced
    at about $40,000, and is designed to compete with such cars as
    the Mercedes SLK and BMW Z3. The Boxster handles better than
    most Porsches. It has a 201-horsepower engine.
</p>
<p>
    The lights explored in the rearview of the black BMW,
    surprising the driver at high speed on the A6 north of
    Stuttgart. He had never seen the little car but could not
    mistake it for anything else - a Porsche, the new Boxster,
    flashing impatiently to pass.
</p>
<p>
    The Boxster is appearing in lots of mirrors on the auto-bahn
    these days, and, sudden as temptation and warped as rumor, in
    the traffic mirrors of narrow-land German villages. This month,
    it comes to the U. S.
</p>
<p>
    But in the mental mirror of the cult of Porsche, the Boxster
    has long been a dreamy image. As a concept car first shown at
    the 1993 Detroit auto show, the Boxster became a legend before
    its own time. Porsche received thousands of orders before
    production was even approved. Fans donned lapel pins of the car
    that read, boxter - ein offenes geheimnis (&quot;an open
    secret&quot;).
</p>
<p>
    Open is the convertible top, made of magnesium in a clever Z
    pattern. Secret is the engine, the 201-horsepower flat six
    hidden in the car&#39;s middle.
</p>
<p>
    The show car was largely the work of Grant Larson, a young
    designer from Milwaukee. But, says Larson&#39;s boss, Porsche
    design chief Harm Lagaay, the car &quot;already existed in the
    imagination&quot; of Porsche customers: They had long dreamed
    of a lighter, less expensive Porsche, in the tradition of the
    midengine 550 Spyder that James Dean drove. It was a hope that
    had been disappointed many times, going back to the 914 of the
    1960s.
</p>
<p>
    Now, in the $40,000 production car, says Lagaay, standing
    beside the test track at Porsche&#39;s top-secret R&amp;D
    facility outside Stuttgart, &quot;we have to make them believe
    what they see.&quot;
</p>
<p>
    The name comes from the combination of boxer - for an engine in
    which cylinders punch in opposite directions - with roadster.
    Although Porsches are traditionally numbered, not named (this
    car would have been the 968), the show-car name continued.
</p>
<p>
    The sound of the new engine is raw, in Porsche tradition. It
    expresses disgust at being run at mere idle, growing
    impatiently, then smoothes out eagerly as the tach climbs.
</p>
<p>
    Its handling is more forgiving (the company uses that very
    word) than that of earlier Porsches, the lines softer, perhaps
    even feminine. The Brembo brake shoes require only about 2.5
    seconds to bring the car from sixty miles per hour to a dead
    stop.
</p>
<p>
    The Boxster will compete with a new generation of roadsters -
    two-seater convertibles like the Mercedes SLK, the BMW
    [Z.sub.3], and the future Audi TTS. All, including the Boxster,
    will be in short supply. One of Porsche&#39;s points of
    differentiation is its twin trunks: The low, midengine design
    leaves room for secret compartments that open fore and aft and
    puts Porsche in the unaccustomed position of bragging about
    cargo space - an oddly practical pitch for a car whose appeal,
    Porsche&#39;s own chairman argues, is based on
    &quot;hedonism.&quot;
</p>
<p>
    Finding the motor is trickier; it&#39;s a secret well kept.
    Lagaay proudly shows how releasing two levers and four small
    fasteners provides engine access. Actual maintenance is done
    from below. If it turns out to be less frequent than on past
    Porsches, there are likely to be more fans becoming buying
    believers than the fifteen thousand cars the factory can turn
    out. The Boxster may be Porsche lite, but it&#39;s a real
    Porsche.
</p>]]></body>
</root>