<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<body><![CDATA[<p>
    The worst thing about the Porsche Boxster is that there was a
    better one a few years ago. At the 1993 Detroit Show, Porsche
    showed a delightful concept car, that looked like today&#39;s
    machine but was studded with jewel-like details, not least a
    gorgeous part-alloy cabin complete with instruments which would
    do justice to any upmarket watch face.
</p>
<p>
    Alas, the production Boxster, just on sale in the UK, has a
    very dull cabin that is made out of the grimmest plastics
    Porsche could find.There are no elegant little fripperies,
    which pepper the rival Mercedes SLK&#39;s cabin. Even the
    switches look and feel rather naff, and are sited with all the
    ergonomic planning of shot fired from a blunderbuss.
</p>
<p>
    Mind you, after a few miles in the Boxster, you probably
    won&#39;t care too much. The little Porsche is such a hoot to
    drive and so stunning to look at that the cheapskate cabin is
    soon dismissed. Instead, you&#39;ll savour the bellow of the
    gutsy flat-six engine, a foot or so behind your ears, and the
    marvellous agility. Like all the best sports cars, the Boxster
    feels alive, hyperactive, eager. And like all other pricier
    Porsche models, it feels solid and meaty when you drive it
    hard. The steering is heavy, even though it&#39;s power
    assisted, and the little short-throw gearchange and pedals have
    firm, precise actions, too. The Boxster replaces the old 968
    model as Porsche&#39;s entry-level machine. It costs just
    pounds 33,950, and that&#39;s cheap for a Porsche. Unlike the
    old 968, the Boxster has a mid-mounted engine, is a full
    convertible, and is very much more distinctive both to look at
    and to drive. It&#39;s an attempt by Porsche to go back to its
    roots and to cast off any criticism of making cars that look
    like Japanese coupes, but cost twice as much. The Boxster harks
    back to the Fifties and to delightful Porsches such as the 550
    Spyder. The Boxster&#39;s mid-engine layout, open top, lowness,
    long nose, headlamp and taillight shapes are reminiscent of the
    famous James Dean sports car, as is the big central rear
    exhaust pipe. The old Spyder was a very minimalist, raw, noisy
    car. The Boxster still has a subversive streak - it&#39;s fast,
    low and noisy, too - but today&#39;s Porsche customers want
    their comforts. The seats are electrically controlled,
    there&#39;s central locking, power windows and an electrically
    operated hood. You can even specify an automatic gearbox, in
    the form of Porsche&#39;s novel Tiptronic S, which enables you
    to choose between full automatic mode or DIY gearchanging
    courtesy of Formula One-type steering wheel buttons. It is such
    a good transmission that you sacrifice little in performance or
    fun compared with standard five-speed manuals. Then again,
    low-rent cabin notwithstanding, you sacrifice so little with
    this car, compared with pounds 50,000-plus Ferraris, that
    there&#39;s little point in spending any more. The Boxster is a
    rebel with a cause - to rewrite the sports car rulebook. After
    the Boxster, there&#39;s just no point in paying any more.
    Porsche Boxster: pounds 33,950. Flat-six cylinder engine,
    204bhp at 6000rpm, two-seater, mid-engined convertible sports
    car. Top speed 149mph, 0-60mph in 6.8 seconds, average fuel
    consumption 27mpg. Rivals Mercedes SLK: pounds 30,090 Cheaper,
    more beautiful, better made and just as fast. But the SLK is
    not as sporty as the Porsche and its supercharged four-cylinder
    engine sounds flat. Automatic transmission only in Britain. BMW
    Z3 2.8: About pounds 26,500. Another highly desirable new
    German convertible, but looks a bit toy-like and not as
    stimulating to drive as the Boxster. TVR Chimera: pounds
    30,650. Beautiful, brutish, fast and noisy. But can&#39;t
    compete with the Germans for refinement, comfort, reliability
    or build quality.
</p>]]></body>
</root>