<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<body><![CDATA[Most one-hit wonders don&#39;t last long. But Porsche, which had
its first (and only) hit as a carmaker back in 1964, is not only
still here, but prospering. And it&#39;s all due to the 911, which
is 33 years old and still going strong.
<br />
<br />
On numerous occasions, the German company has tried to replace it,
fearing its time had finally come. But each time ­ most notably
when it launched the 928 in 1978 ­ buyers have spurned the
newcomer, preferring the more characterful if less conventional
charms of the old-timer.
<br />
<br />
The new Boxster is an obvious follow-up to the 911. It comes at a
time when sales of affordable convertible sports cars are booming.
The marvelous Mazda Miata, known as the MX-5 in Europe, proved the
market existed. Now the German sporty big three (BMW, Mercedes and
Porsche) are all in there, exchanging punches. Even the British
maker MG, which virtually invented the affordable roadster market,
is back.
<br />
<br />
The Old and the New
<br />
<br />
The Boxster carries over many 911 styling cues ­ its buglike
roundness, its curvaceous fenders and its lowness. But mechanically
it&#39;s all new. The engine may be a flat-six, but this motor is
different. It&#39;s smaller and less powerful than the 911&#39;s
engine, true to the Boxster&#39;s lower price and more mass-market
aspirations. In keeping with its clean-sheet approach, the engine
is sited in the middle of the car ­ between the cabin and the rear
wheels ­ rather than out the back, keeping the rear bumper company.
A mid-engine configuration is much better for handling.
<br />
<br />
It is a fabulous car to drive, the Boxster, the best in the class.
It&#39;s brisker and sharper than the rival Mercedes SLK, prettier
and faster than the BMW Z3. The engine has that same marvelous
bellow that characterizes the 911: Hit the accelerator pedal and
the motor trumpets like a bull elephant. The handling is almost
hyperactively sensitive ­ the car wends its way down winding roads
like a snake speeding through long grass ­ and the fabulous brakes
and steering just add to the dynamic ensemble. The drop-down roof,
fully electric apart from some manual work to tether it to the
windshield, just adds to the thrills and to the raw sensations that
are part of the character of the best sports cars.
<br />
The cabin design is the biggest disappointment. The plastics are
not of especially good quality and the switches are sited across
the dash with all the ergonomic planning of shot fired from a
blunderbuss. As with the 911, you buy a Boxster for the way the
outside looks and for the way it drives, not for any particular
enjoyment to be had from the cabin ambience.
<br />
<br />
Porsche&#39;s recent creative rush, incidentally, isn&#39;t over
yet. The one-hit wonders from Stuttgart are set to revamp the 911
at the end of the year, further upgrading the old-timer. After all,
if the unexpected happens and the market turns against the new
Boxster, then at least there&#39;s the 911 to fall back on.
<br />
Porsche Boxster. About $50,000. Flat-six engine, 2,480cc, 204 BHP
at 6,000 rpm. Five-speed manual gearbox, five-speed automatic
&#39;&#39;Tiptronic&#39;&#39; transmission optional. Top speed: 240
kph (149 mph). Acceleration: 0-100 kph in 6.9 seconds. Average fuel
consumption: 10.2 liters/100 km.]]></body>
</root>