<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
		<body><![CDATA[<p>
    The economy has a case of the jitters and sales of the
    lowest-priced Porsche go down while sales of the highest-priced
    Porsche go up.
</p>
<p>
    Sales of the Boxster (starting at $42,600 to $52,000) slid to
    8,118 units in the first nine months of this year from 10,071
    in the same period a year ago, while sales of the 911 (starting
    at $67,000 to $180,000) rose to 8,779 units from 7,907.
</p>
<p>
    Porsche North America, the U.S. distributor, even put
    incentives on Boxster to help move unsold inventory, offering
    $1,000 in cash to members of the Porsche Club of America to
    help dispose of inventory.
</p>
<p>
    Unfortunately, it forgot to tell the brass in Germany of the
    incentive offer. Porsche execs in the home country considered
    the rebate offer a gimmick that hinted at a distress sale and
    slighted the sports car&#39;s image, not to mention its value.
</p>
<p>
    Porsche North America won&#39;t do that again.
</p>
<p>
    There were two reasons Boxster sales declined, Porsche says.
    One is that enthusiasts knew Boxster was going to get a
    facelift for `03 and so they held back on a purchase of an `02
    until the upgraded model arrived.
</p>
<p>
    The other is that some Porsche buyers, just like those who
    purchase a Ford, Chevy or Toyota, are affected by the economy.
</p>
<p>
    &quot;The Boxster buyer is 35 to 45 years of age, earns
    $100,000 plus, and is a manager or supervisor whose job is
    affected by the economy,&quot; explained Porsche spokesman Bob
    Carlson.
</p>
<p>
    &quot;The 911 buyer, however, is 45 to 55, earns $200,000 plus,
    and is an entrepreneur whose job isn&#39;t as affected by the
    economy,&quot; Thomas said.
</p>
<p>
    So when the economy is shaky, the boss buys a 911, the employee
    holds off purchasing a Boxster.
</p>
<p>
    Oh, well, at least we&#39;re talking cars and not stock
    options.
</p>
<p>
    Which brings us to the `03 Boxster, or what some refer to as
    the poor man&#39;s 911 _ though most would have difficulty
    considering anyone earning $100,000 a year to be a
    down-and-outer, much less a person in need of a $1,000 rebate.
</p>
<p>
    Boxster is offered in base and top-of-the-line S versions. We
    tested the base, which like the S has undergone its first
    significant styling change since it first appeared in the 1997
    model year.
</p>
<p>
    Subtle changes were made to the body to make it more
    aerodynamic to slither through the air without power and
    fuel-robbing disruptions. For `03 there&#39;s a more rounded
    roofline, lower rear end and newly designed cooling air intakes
    that give the front end a lower look while providing more
    airflow to the engine.
</p>
<p>
    The `03 Boxster is so aerodynamic you can drive in the rain
    with the top down and not a drop of water will enter the cabin
    to splatter your melon, boasts Carlson.
</p>
<p>
    Of course, to ensure the magic to keep you dry you must
    purchase the optional windblocker ($375), a stand-up plastic
    barrier behind the seats which keeps air passing over the car
    from traveling back into the cabin, and you must travel at no
    less than 45 mph.
</p>
<p>
    &quot;Under 45 mph and you&#39;re on your own,&quot; Carlson
    says.
</p>
<p>
    As for the top, pull one release lever, push a button, and it
    powers down and out of sight in 12 seconds. Thanks to the new,
    more rounded design of the top, you can slip into and out of
    the car without bumping the noggin.
</p>
<p>
    Boxster also boasts both increased power as well as fuel
    economy for `03.
</p>
<p>
    Thanks to new variable cam technology, the 2.7-liter 6-cylinder
    in the Boxster now delivers 225 h.p., up from 217 h.p. (258
    h.p., up from 250 in the S).
</p>
<p>
    The mileage rating goes to 20 m.p.g. city/29 m.p.g. highway
    from 19/27 for `02 (18/26 for the S, same as `02).
</p>
<p>
    The most noteworthy upgrade for `03 is that to increase
    longevity, the two-seat roadster now sports a glass rear window
    with built-in defroster rather than plastic, which could
    discolor or crack. The glass also helps reduce noise filtering
    back into the cabin when the top is up.
</p>
<p>
    One other change is a redesign of the cupholders. Rather than
    two holders popping out of the dash at the same time, one now
    slips from its housing, and then pull and a second holder
    emerges.
</p>
<p>
    You might argue that upgrading cupholders makes little sense in
    a 225-h.p. sports car, but keep in mind that hot coffee in the
    lap is far more aggravating than cold rainwater on the scalp.
</p>
<p>
    One feature left unchanged: Boxster continues to be fun to
    drive. Kick the pedal and the 2.7-liter six springs to life and
    the smooth 5-speed manual helps get all the energy out of the
    six. A speed-activated rear spoiler automatically rises when
    you reach 75 mph to keep you better planted to the road and
    then retracts when you ease back to 50 mph.
</p>
<p>
    For serious motoring, opt for Porsche&#39;s stability
    management system with traction control, a $1,235 option that
    helps keep the car going in the direction pointed on slippery
    or dry roads. Sensors detect any loss of grip front or rear and
    automatically apply braking to the slipping wheel or wheels and
    reduce engine power to maintain stability.
</p>
<p>
    No free lunch, however. You&#39;ll feel most of the tar marks
    in the road thanks to a stiff suspension designed for optimum
    handling at the expense of cushioned ride.
</p>
<p>
    You&#39;ll have to accept occasional up-and-down gyrations for
    the ability to make tight corners and turns, which, of course,
    is one of the primary reasons you consider Boxster in the first
    place.
</p>
<p>
    Base price of the Boxster is $42,600. Standard equipment in
    addition to that noted includes four-wheel anti-lock brakes,
    dual front and side impact air bags, power
    windows/seats/locks/mirrors (heated), leather seats, automatic
    climate control, digital radio with in-dash CD player and fog
    lights.
</p>
<p>
    There&#39;s also front and rear luggage compartments, or what
    Porsche calls front and rear trunks. The two-seater doesn&#39;t
    have a lot of space to carry items in the cabin, and really not
    much more in those trunks.
</p>
<p>
    Boxster is a midengine machine with the engine directly behind
    the driver. This means the normal engine compartment up front
    now serves as a minitrunk. Space reserved for the stored power
    top makes for a tiny trunk in back. Boxster holds the golf
    clubs, though it holds them in the passenger seat.
</p>
<p>
    The test vehicle came with optional 18-inch alloy Carrera
    wheels at $2,920 (17-inch in `02); wheel caps with colored
    crest at $175, cruise control at $570, remote keyless entry at
    $450 (until you decipher the trio of key fob buttons, you can
    unlock either trunk when simply wanting to unlock the doors), a
    Hi-Fi digital sound upgrade (six speakers rather than two for
    concert-hall sound) at $830, seal gray metallic paint at $825
    and graphite gray floor mats at $95.
</p>
<p>
    It didn&#39;t come with the $2,630 navigation system. If smart
    enough to earn $100,000 a year, do you need a satellite
    circling overhead to tell you that you&#39;re 5 miles from
    home?
</p>
<p>
    Next up from Porsche, the Cayenne, its first sport-utility
    vehicle due out in the first quarter of next year with a choice
    of 340-h.p. or 450-h.p. turbocharged 4.5-liter V-8 engine.
    <br />
    2003 Porsche Boxster
</p>
<p>
    Wheelbase: 95.1 inches
    <br />
    Length: 170.1 inches
    <br />
    Engine: 2.7-liter, 225-h.p. 6-cylinder
    <br />
    Transmission: 5-speed manual
    <br />
    Fuel economy: 20 m.p.g. city/29 m.p.g. highway
    <br />
    Base price: $42,600
    <br />
    Price as tested: $49,625. Includes $825 for seal gray metallic
    paint; $2,920 for 18-inch Carrera wheels; $175 for wheel caps
    with Porsche crest; $570 for cruise control; $1,235 for
    stability control; $375 for windstop deflector; $95 for
    graphite gray floor mats; and $830 for digital hi-fi sound
    system. Add $765 for freight.
</p>
<p>
    Pluses: First design update since it was introduced in 1997.
    Boost in horsepower. Addition of glass rear window. Still fun
    to drive, especially with retractable top down.
</p>
<p>
    Minuses: So many options to sort out&nbsp;and pay for.
</p>]]></body>
</root>